Are you ready for combat?
Are you ready to put on your warfare boots, your warfare gloves, and your warfare goggles?
Because I am Isaac is...
We're heading into battle.
I require your strongest potions.
Can you feel it?
We're going through all the motions.
Man, I've been missing Isaac.
Haha!
I have so many plans today.
You don't even believe me, if I tell you.
Haha!
Quite your strongest pills.
Fuck, I should have said that.
I couldn't think of anything in the in the moment.
Are we a Zazil-ing?
You know what actually?
Maybe we should do a quick warm-up as a Zazil.
I don't know.
We'll see.
Maybe I'll change my mind.
We're gonna do challenges today.
We're gonna do all kinds of characters.
We're gonna fuck in everything.
We're gonna do everything.
In fact, I'm gonna complete the game today.
This is the last Isaac stream.
That's right, you heard me.
Because we're gonna be done today.
We're never gonna be undone.
Because we're done.
It's all finished.
Challenges, check.
Isaac, check.
Characters unlock, check.
Just kidding.
We're doing a lot of streams.
Because I have a feeling it's gonna take a while.
What are you guys ready for Isaac?
Are you ready for Isaac?
Can you feel the Isaac?
Can you hear the Isaac?
Isaac is coming!
He's going into battle!
Okay, let's tone it down a bit.
I need to conserve some energy.
I need it for later.
Hahaha!
Right, I gotta check some endings as well.
That's true.
Let's see what I wrote here.
Let's see if you guys can see it.
Check out ending 10 in stats menu.
Right here.
That's the one right there.
So I'm gonna go ahead and do that.
In a second.
Let's do this.
We do the transition.
BAM!
Take me into the universe of Isaac.
Let's see here.
Stats.
Endings.
Ending 10.
Wait.
Oh, wait a minute!
I'm over halfway done with the game.
Look at this!
Final!
Hahaha!
Let's see what I found.
We're gonna see the butt though.
He spoke!
What the frick is that?
Wait a minute, what is ending 9?
I probably missed some of these actually.
What did he find this time?
Oh, that was that one.
Okay, so I think I've seen everything else.
Let me just double check.
I'm just gonna go through a couple more.
This is like the experience of playing Call of Duty.
Oh, wait, that's new!
25!
You know, this is like the Call of Duty or the Counter-Strike stream or is it Fortnite?
Well, you just open chests all day, you know, you get randomized loot.
Hahaha!
We're opening loot boxes!
What am I gonna get?
Oh, that's all, wait, that's also new!
It's some kind of syringe.
What the fuck?
Is that the result of using too many syringes?
Guys, I spent over a thousand dollars on DLC in Repentance here.
Like, I bought all the chests, all the loot boxes.
I spent so much money on it.
I'm actually addicted.
Yeah, he was crying this time.
I feel like that's new.
I hate that laugh because it it portends a big hand coming down, you know?
Okay, you know what?
Secrets?
Let me see here.
You unlocked a nerd and there's a dick drawn in the book as well.
A dick antenna.
And then we have Magdalene.
Oh, wait, that's new!
I don't think I've been able to play her before.
Cain?
Okay, that's old.
Judas?
Okay, this is a while ago.
Got it.
Okay.
Let's go crazy.
Who am I?
Guys, win streak of two!
Holy shit!
Can we make it to three?
We gotta play a sasle just to make it to three.
I've never been at three.
Hold on, so we have Eve?
The poop?
Wait, what is this?
I can play it.
Minus one HP?
Doesn't sound good.
Oh, wait, Magdalene we have played.
I'm an idiot.
It's the one with the young heart.
Isaac, Jacob, it's not unlocked yet.
Not unlocked, not unlocked.
I have three Eden tokens.
Okay, I'm not entirely sure what's going on there.
Samsung, this one I played already.
Eve is the whore, right?
This is new.
This one is new.
I will play that today, but we're gonna start with an sasle and the reason is I can't lose my win streak guys.
I'm at two!
I'm in the skies right now.
I can't believe, like, we can't lose this.
We have to win.
We gotta make it to three.
And we start off with poop.
That's horrible.
I guess it can spawn items for me.
Let's use it a lot.
As often as possible.
I almost got hit there, that was atrocious.
We're totally pilling then.
Lemon party.
We got the fool in case we need to make a hasty exit from a certain room.
Okay, you're gonna shoot at me.
Let's look for rocks here.
I see no suspicious rocks.
Let's have a poop in here.
I mean a peek.
A poop and a peek.
Humbling bundle.
More money and red hearts and keys and bombs.
Okay, okay, okay.
That's pretty good, but I don't have the money for that, unfortunately.
Moving on.
I gotta get into it.
Poop a bit.
There we go.
BAM.
Majero.
Nice, nice.
I need, like, at least 15 minutes to get back into the groove of things here.
It's been a while since I played this game.
Oh, wait, I can fly!
Haha, right.
I almost forgot.
Yeah, I mean just I'm just grabbing this, no problem.
Oh, that was another room.
I love the drive-by.
Oi!
Look at that one!
Holy shit!
That's massive!
Just like that?
Wow.
I'm not taking it yet, though.
We're going in here.
Nice!
And then we're gonna do this!
Optimal gameplay!
It doesn't get better than this.
Are you ready?
Are you ready, kids?
It's the Duke of Flies.
We're gonna have perfect gameplay today.
That's amazing.
We got luck and another soul heart and more keys.
Amazing.
We're gonna go back now and grab this, because we're not gonna forget that, no way.
Poop as well.
Optimalization.
Very good.
And I think we're about done here.
No, no, no, wait.
We got two coins.
No, we don't have enough for the shop.
Moving on.
Man, this doesn't get better than that.
This is the best first floor I've ever had.
Why am I always so lucky when I play the Ace?
You know?
The Ace in the hole.
The Azazel.
Come here.
Oh, you almost touched me there.
I feel like the pooping the poop is not very useful.
A lot of the times it doesn't yield anything.
Uh-oh.
Oh, no way!
I can't believe I got hit by that guy.
It's okay, though.
Hey, sir.
You want to dance?
Okay.
Let's go here.
Make a poop.
I'm kind of proud of myself for remembering my active right now.
Like, it's not the best active, but I'm consistently remembering it.
That's something.
And you know what?
There could be an eternal heart in there.
So it's worth doing, right?
We got any special rocks here?
It doesn't look like it.
Those guys are the worst.
He was camouflaged.
That little bastard.
That was beautiful.
Actually, I should go in here before I destroy the poop.
Just in case.
This is... let me see if I can predict it without looking.
This is the book of...
Actually, I don't know.
Okay, I would never have guessed that.
Book of shadows.
Gain a damage nullifying shield.
That's good!
That is pretty damn good.
I think it's better than the poop.
It keeps me safe.
And this room is clear, right?
Nothing in the rocks.
Nothing in the walls.
We love that.
Dude, this is good.
Like, we're going to kick ass today.
I can just feel it.
It's one of those days, you know?
Lovely.
Let's also not forget, I'm starting to amass a little bit of money here.
So, it's soon time for the shop.
Wait, what's going on here?
Someone over here?
Ah!
I see.
Come on, give me that eternal heart again.
Show it to me.
I can't believe I got that from a poop.
I guess it depends on luck as well.
How much do you want to bet there's a secret room right here?
Let me actually bomb from this side.
Fuck yeah!
You know how I knew?
Well, not that I knew, but...
You see how I was just surrounded by rooms?
It was almost...
There's gotta be something there, right?
And I was right.
Okay.
Let's do a... bomb on you?
Actually, no.
I feel like I shouldn't waste my bombs.
I keep doing that.
But I guess sometimes I get items from it.
Ah, wait a sec, I don't want to go back yet.
Or go forward yet.
I want to go back first.
This one is still closed.
I don't have a fool.
So, we're gonna lose a soul heart here.
But it's okay.
Pills!
Okay, balls of steel, I don't know what does.
Oh wait, it gives me HP.
I should note it down.
Balls of steel, let me move this down here.
Balls of steel?
I think it's two soul hearts?
Let me see.
Help down...
Right, okay, okay.
That seems good to me.
Okay, this one's useless.
Bob's curse!
Bomb damage, poisons, enemies.
Do I want this?
I think I do, it's just a good item.
Like, there's no downsides.
I should have used my protective shield here.
That's how I should have gotten through this without losing half a heart.
I'll know that for later.
It just occurred to me.
Better late than never, right?
Okay, I'm going to pre-charge my massive attack, and we're going to go in here and kick ass.
Maybe I'll even activate it now, and just go nuts.
It's ten seconds, right?
Like, it's crazy.
Whoa.
Beautiful.
Absolutely destroyed.
And we got a wire coat hanger, that's good.
Fast to charge for me.
And we have this.
Uh oh, evil fires.
I'm not going to fall for it.
Not falling for that.
Okay, what is that one?
The mark, black heart, more...
That's good.
We take it.
And this one is chance to drop a soul heart when taking damage.
Chance to drop a half red heart when killing an enemy.
Uh, yeah.
Yeah, this is fantastic.
Maybe I'm not understanding exactly how that works.
How come I didn't grab it the first time?
That's confusing.
Oh well.
Now I have a lot of good stuff.
We go to the shop.
Oh, there's a chest here.
Fuck yeah.
We even have a health we can pick up in the boss room.
Incredible.
Pills are amazing.
Love eating pills.
We can even eat this too.
But wait, this one is discounted.
One additional item will appear in treasure rooms.
Ooh.
Yes, I think I like that.
Oh, I thought it was an active for some reason.
But yeah, great.
Now for the remaining, I think I'm actually gonna...
Let me see.
I'm gonna buy this.
Yep, I'm doing it.
Dude, look how much HP I have on the second floor.
How crazy is that?
I feel like this is unheard of.
In the Binding of Isaac community.
This has never before been seen.
Cheers.
Let's go.
Yo, C.
Daisy.
Let's go down here.
This is how you deal with these guys.
Aha!
A fight room.
Lovely.
We're gonna shoot?
Yeah.
You actually hit me with that.
Oh my god.
Dude, this guy's a sniper.
Okay, you gotta do drive-bys on those guys.
I learned my lesson.
An amazing key we got!
The door in the distance opened.
We gotta find that door today.
Uh, sure?
Uh-oh.
Sir!
Uh, the bean releases a fart.
No, thanks.
What is that?
That's new.
Scatter bombs?
We put bombs in your bombs?
Yo, dawg.
Uh, bomb explosions released to- Ooh, wait.
I don't like that very much.
Actually.
Because I feel like that's gonna hurt me more than the enemy.
Unless I'm really careful.
We'll see how it goes.
But I had to see what it was, right?
Yeah, the drive-by method is actually paramount on Azazel.
Come here!
Nice.
There's something on my hands.
Okay.
It's gone now.
I caught my hands yesterday.
While making food.
I haven't caught my hands in a long, long time.
So much so that I didn't even have, like, a band-aid.
I had to improvise with, uh...
What do you call it?
One of those elastic bands and some kitchen towel.
Hahaha!
It works!
It got the job done.
I'll go.
Yeah, drive-by on these guys, for sure.
Oh, I still got hit.
It's because of this layout here.
Oh my god, dude!
Okay.
Tough one.
Lovely.
Uh, no tinted rocks in here.
It's all clear.
And that's the boss.
Not yet, though.
We're doing a complete eradication of this floor.
Oh, you can't reach me down here.
I never ran into those spikes.
Dumbasses.
They have been pooping in a very systematic way here.
Come on, give me another Eternal Heart in the poop.
It's weird that these flies over here don't classify as enemies.
Like, the doors open, you know?
Before they die.
He wants keys!
Wait!
Did I just give him my special key?
That was a special animation just now.
Um...
I mean, I'll take this for the keys and then I'll take the other one back.
Thanks.
I'm not sure what just occurred there.
I think I just gave up my special key.
Mom's coin purse.
I don't have a lot of money.
What's this?
We don't know what it is.
I'm gonna save my money.
Wait, do I want this?
Consumes a key to launch, a sharpened key, that the key damages and pierces enemies.
Uh...
I mean, destroys obstacles.
And enemies killed by the key protectile have a chance to drop pickups.
Okay, that is actually pretty sick.
But I feel like I should be using this if I have, like, insanely many keys.
Actually, you know what?
Grab it.
Yeah, I'm gonna use this.
Fuck it.
It'll be okay.
Oh!
Oh.
I don't know why that happens sometimes and other times it doesn't.
What is it with me getting flight when I'm playing as Seizel?
How about giving it to me on the other characters?
It's every time.
A little brimstone?
That would be fitting, wouldn't it?
I could give him three hearts for that, I guess.
Uh, yeah, we don't need that at all.
Oh, this one is pretty cool.
You know what?
I feel like we need to use this.
I gotta get this.
It's just too damn cool.
I'm gonna go dig.
It's digging time, baby.
And we got pills as well.
Oh, that sucks.
Well, that was not great.
That's what happens when you gamble, kids.
Wait, I see a potential secret room.
Yep, yep, yep.
Right here.
Watch me.
Okay, I was wrong.
But wait, there's one right here.
No, there's not.
Hmm.
I gotta start looking for secret rooms.
I have 18 bombs.
Uh, how about up here?
No.
Hmm.
Dude, I bet this bomb is super powerful against bosses.
Also, we gotta look for X's in Texas.
Maybe this one?
Come on, man.
Look for those X's.
No X here.
Nothing there.
I must have missed an X.
I mean, this area is huge.
And I feel like there's X's everywhere.
Nothing here.
I am aware that I'm giving away all of my red hearts.
I've been acquiring...
This may come back and bite me in the ass.
So I gotta acquire more.
To make up for that.
Uh, no X's here.
Hmm.
Not in there.
Okay, you know what?
Let's try and blow this up.
I have a feeling.
There's just no secret rooms today.
I wonder if it's guaranteed that there's always a secret room.
Maybe there isn't.
Let's try here.
Nope.
Oh, you know what?
Actually, maybe at the very end of one of these...
Down near the, um...
The item room.
Right here.
Brother man.
That was five bombs wasted so far.
Actually six, I think.
And no X's.
Crazy.
Okay, here.
I don't actually believe that.
Maybe it's not every time.
Maybe a secret room.
Ahoy!
Look at that!
Nice!
Okay, boss time.
It's pestilence.
Oh, that's too bad.
I blew you up.
Ah, that wasn't too bad.
Except I hate this item.
Uh, levels up each time it is collected.
Yeah, I mean, I may as well take it, right?
Uh, this one, right?
Do I want to do this?
Do I maybe want to take the little brimstone?
I mean, I already have... I mean, okay, wait a minute.
This guy has infinite range, right?
Three blue hearts.
I'm assuming it's not going to consume any black hearts I have?
Since it says three blue hearts?
Hmm...
I mean, I am really...
Okay.
No, this may be a mistake.
I've been giving up all of my HP now.
Okay, from now on, we're going to start working on increasing HP.
This is more than enough.
We don't need to go further than that.
It's okay, and look for axes.
Oh, God.
I can use this guy for extra... Look at that, look at that.
It's actually amazing.
Kill him.
I'm playing it so safe.
Did I get him?
No.
He has a lot of HP.
Nice!
And what is this?
Less speed, no thanks.
I'll, uh...
I'll skip that.
What's that?
Duck tape.
Familius will stick in there... Oh, wait a sec!
That's really good!
Wait, wait, I need to, uh...
I need this guy to be right on top of me.
I mean, that's... Hold on.
We can do it even better.
Look at that!
Actually, we can do it better.
He's not exactly on top of me.
What about now?
Yeah, look at that!
Look at that!
Dude, I'm a genius.
This is so good!
I have Brimstone now.
Oh god.
Except the charge on the little guy is a little... longer than mine.
So it's a little awkward, but yeah.
Now I just need that item that amplifies my damage when, uh...
Or in front of me, I forget which it is.
But you know the one.
That item I need now.
Uh, deals 40 damage.
Okay, that's fine, I guess.
Yeah, the fact that it's charging a little slower than my main attack is...
kind of...
screwing with me a little bit.
Nice.
Uh, more pills?
I mean, that's fine.
Yeah.
That's okay, I like it.
Let's look for suspicious rocks.
I see none.
And no axes?
No axes.
Hmm, what's that?
Diplopia duplicates all pickups and item pedestals in the room.
Um, I mean, that's pretty cool.
But not right now.
I'm not feeling it.
This room is weird.
Uh, let's go here.
Playing it's so safe.
Oh, what am I doing?
Very good.
Okay, this is the secret room.
No it ain't!
Dude.
There's no secret rooms today, they don't exist.
Oh god.
Peek your head up.
Also, I'm not seeing my HP, I just realized.
Shit.
I gotta be extra careful.
Oh god.
I gotta charge them up a bit more, there we go.
Okay, here though.
I can't believe it.
Lovely.
And we got a boss here.
Also, maybe I missed an X.
X, X, X, X, X, X.
No, no, no, no, I don't see any...
Okay.
Let's go here.
Oh, this room is annoying.
But not when I'm playing Azazel.
And it's quite comfortable.
Okay, here though.
Oh man.
Oh wait, I think I checked from the other side, so that was a bit of a waste.
That was on me.
What's going on here?
Oh, I see.
You're not gonna turn off?
Okay, you're not gonna turn off.
Uh, oh wait, what is...
I feel like I've seen that before, why is it not shown?
Wandering Familia that spawns friendly blue attack spiders.
That's not too good with me when I have the Scotch tape.
I like this, let's try it.
Oh, teleport 2.0.
Teleport to an uncleared room in order of priority.
Square white room first, and then comes boss room.
Secret room.
Whoa, cool.
Alright.
Oh, but wait, we're giving up this shovel.
I guess I'll come back for that, I'm gonna teleport.
Okay, so it took me to the boss room, which means the square room does not exist, whatever it is.
The white square is non-existent.
Oh god, that was bad.
Solid boss fight.
You unlocked something new.
Health!
Huge!
We need that.
Unfortunately, we do not have a deal.
Man, I cannot believe there's no X's.
Let me check that room where I have to go inside and...
Ah, but then I lose HP.
Let's just move on.
Wait, I have 14 monies.
Was there something I wanted to buy?
Let's check.
There was definitely a soul heart I could purchase if I needed to.
Yeah, I could buy that.
Oh, I can almost buy that.
Hold on.
Coin me.
No.
What was this again?
Oh, I don't actually want that.
Yeah, fuck that.
It's an active as well, I think.
Let's take this.
We're playing it mega safe.
Mega safe.
So I'm actually gonna disregard the shovel.
Because I feel like this teleport thing is super interesting.
Let me see here.
So we have the white square.
Boss, then secret.
If I had... Oh, you know what I should do?
I should teleport as soon as I get to the next level.
Because then I can accumulate more energy and start teleporting to more areas.
Alright, we're gonna need a bit more energy first though.
So we're gonna do this.
Uh-oh, not these guys.
Good thing I have infinite range.
Hey, nice!
My active... Oh, not my active, my item.
Where are you, son?
Okay.
For like three bombs, I don't know if that was worth it, perhaps.
Man, these guys have a lot of HP.
The tankiest flies I've ever seen.
Man, it's so comfortable having the laser against those guys.
How much do you want to bet we're gonna find dick spots immediately now, because we don't have the shovel anymore.
Oh, I can actually teleport again.
Let's do it.
It's probably gonna be the boss.
No?
Wait, what?
So this is the white room.
Okay.
What's this?
Got it.
I still have some extra HP lying around.
What's that?
Mysterious candy?
Okay.
Ah, replaces this one.
I don't know if I like that button.
I'm gonna have to rearrange this.
Uh, come to me.
Let's see.
Beautiful.
Good enough.
Uh, broken remote.
It triggers the teleport effect each time an active item is used.
Wait, what?
It's like the ultimate teleportation setup.
You know what?
Let's do it.
I don't care about this, uh, glue anyway.
This is gonna be fun.
Uh, let's not go in there yet.
Oh, maybe I regret it now, actually.
It is nice to have it aligned perfectly every time.
I admit it.
Uh, there's one more.
There you are.
Oh my god.
Awesome.
I'm still looking for X's, even though I don't need to.
They hit me.
No, they didn't.
Okay, we're fine.
Uh, best friend.
Places a decoy that draws enemies to it and explodes.
Uh, I'm finding so many actives today.
What is that?
My reflection.
Boomerang.
Whoa, wait a minute.
Plus six range?
More... ooh!
My reflection.
That is in crazy amount of range.
Boomerang tiers.
0.1.6 shot speed multiplier.
What?
Oh, that's... wait.
Yeah, that's kind of cool.
I like that, except...
I don't... maybe the idea is to shoot backwards now or something?
No, it's definitely okay like this.
That's fine.
Oh, that's not an enemy.
Definitely good for AOE.
Don't hit those stones.
What is it with me always being at 14 when I enter these shops?
Shit.
Uh, we don't know what that pill is.
Jar of flies.
So many actives!
I don't need more actives.
What was that one?
Reveal special rooms!
Okay, we gotta get that one.
I think this is a passive.
I like that.
Because I've been meaning to find specials this entire... or not specials, uh, secrets.
Uh, wait a minute.
Should I be doing this?
No.
The answer is nope.
Oh, yeah, the backwards shot is actually so nice.
Oh, look at that guy!
Champion!
He dropped the key, I guess.
Not super exciting.
Uh, let's try the teleport.
Let's see how it goes.
Okay.
Yeah, I'm not sure what's happening.
Just a random room.
Lovely.
We got the money now.
Heading back.
Oh, man, the gravity field is super strong.
It was up here.
Oh, look, there's an X!
Fuck!
Finally found one.
Can't use it, though.
Oh, it's not even a passive!
Or, I mean, a, uh...
You know, drink it.
Fantastic.
So, let's see.
Wait.
It actually did say special.
I thought I was gaslighting myself.
I think I wanted that to say secret.
Aw, man!
Alright.
Time to manually search again.
I can't believe it.
Here's for sure, right?
Let me try and teleport again.
Mom!
Gotta be more.
No?
Okay.
Right there.
I swear secrets don't exist today!
Wait, did I find something?
Emergency contact!
Spawns to Mom's hands that damage and pin enemies.
I think it's better than what I had there.
I don't believe it!
I... Hold on a minute.
There's no way!
Let's bomb this.
I've never been this unlucky!
Oh, god.
No, there should not be anything up there.
What about here?
It is existing!
Lost contact!
Less shot speed, tears collide with and destroy enemy...
That's really good!
That is fantastic.
Actually...
Keep going.
Yeah!
Oh, wait.
Right.
Let's just keep bombing, though.
I want to find more secrets.
Let's try here.
Damn.
Alright, time for the boss.
Wish me luck.
It is Mask of Infamy, okay.
That means we go for the heart, of course.
Wonderful.
That was no problem at all.
Oh, a lot of range, baby!
The range feels less...
I feel like I got less range.
It's like more range backwards.
I don't like that!
Mino likey!
Blood oath, stabs Isaac...
at the start of each floor, deleting as many red hearts as it can...
without killing him.
The stab grants bonus damage and speed for the rest of the floor.
The more health sacrificed to this effect, the more stats...
Oh!
We don't have any red hearts anyway, should we go crazy?
Dude!
I kinda wanna go crazy.
Ah, but wait a minute, stepping on this is gonna cost me HP as well.
Actually, no, no, no, no, no.
I'm gonna be too low, it's gonna be horrible.
Absolutely not.
I think I'm done here.
Yeah.
It's time for mom!
This is the mom floor.
What a fantastic first run of the day here.
You cannot complain about that.
I'm gonna teleport.
I regret not keeping my shovel.
100% regret that.
Oh my god, really?
You actually hit me.
Yeah, the teleport thing here is kinda bad.
Oh yeah, right, I can't take damage from this now.
Cause I'm flying.
Or chilling.
Ooh, uh...
Mine is unlucky, so I don't think so, buddy.
I will blow you up, though.
Yeah.
Hey, massive!
Wait!
Wait a minute.
Did I just get that from the fire?
Didn't it look like it spawned out of the fire?
Jim!
Dude, I was so fast, I didn't even have time to react.
Oh god.
Oh, we could go step-ity-step, but that's not happening with my current setup.
Alright, mom.
Come on, then.
Do your worst.
This has gotta be health down.
Watch.
Okay, pheromones.
That's cool.
Nice.
It's greed.
Oh, dude, we should do greed mode today, actually.
Let's do a little bit of greed mode, as well.
That sounds fun.
Fuck!
I didn't mean to do that.
It was a mistak.
That was way too risky what I just did there.
I don't know why I did that.
That was stupid.
Luckily, I didn't get punished for it, but, you know, I easily could have been.
I'm rich!
Let's find the shop, baby.
Okay, that's pretty cool.
I'm doing a lot of damage.
I like it.
Oh, what do we got here?
Pills?
Or?
Bloodwrights take one heart of self-damage to gain a tears up and deal 40 damage subsequent uses.
No way, we're taking the pills.
Abba, wait!
I'm gonna teleport now, as well, when I do this.
Wait a second.
I'm gonna drop this thing.
I don't actually like that.
No, thanks.
Oh.
Full health.
Ah, okay, well, there it is.
It's fine.
Oh, god!
Okay.
What do we have here?
Full health?
Hey!
We can use that.
Abba, wait!
That's not gonna heal my black hearts.
It's only red hearts, so kinda...
This one sucks, as well.
Let's just use it, I guess.
Get it out of the system.
I like this more.
Don't you dare do that crap.
Okay.
Ah, should we go for the boss?
It's mom!
Actually, let's not.
Not yet.
Oh, god!
I hit the moving platform!
Okay, okay.
Take me in here, man.
Ooh, look at all this stuff.
Health up!
What's that?
Rescue solids!
Balls of steel.
Spiders!
Okay, that's not so cool, I guess, but...
Oh, that's not cool at all.
What about this one?
No!
This one.
Oh, my god!
I just got another heart!
Am I gonna spend it already?
The pact, damage... Oh, two black hearts?
Ooh, do I exchange all my red hearts for the black hearts?
Ooh, I'm doing it!
Hahaha, I'm naughty as hell!
Oh, man, that's naughty.
I feel kind of bad about that.
I deserve to die now.
I deserve to die.
Nah, it'll be fine.
It'll be fine.
We gotta explore the rest, though.
Go in here.
There goes one of the hearts.
Let's not do that again, huh?
We also have emergency contact.
What was that again?
Two mom's hands that damage and pin enemies.
Okay.
I guess we'll use that against mom.
We're gonna use her hands against herself.
And go, why are you hitting yourself?
You know, like you used to do when you were young?
Okay, wait, I'm going the wrong way here.
I also want to spawn more pills.
Wait, I have 24 monies.
Dude, let's go back to the shop, actually.
Wasn't there something amazing in the shop?
I want soul hearts.
Soul hearts would be a clutch right now.
Ah, shit, okay.
I think I was thinking of the last one.
Let's look for secrets, then.
Let's go inside the stability room.
Just have a look.
Wait, counter fit penny?
50% chance to gain one additional cent each time you pick up a coin.
Cents and coins.
Okay.
Blow this up.
There's got to be something there.
Or not.
All right, then.
Here?
I mean, I may as well look for secrets with the...
Oh, wait, did I just find some?
I got so many bombs, right?
So...
Maybe here.
No, here?
Why are they so hard to find?
Okay, there's nothing here.
When there's like a little bit of airspace, there's almost never a secret room.
Not in my experience.
Let's do one here.
Yes, dude!
More money!
Crazy.
Goodnight.
Step into my... gas.
Oh!
I didn't mean to push that bomb.
We're not going to open this.
That's no use.
Okay, so that's one secret.
But what about second secret?
Damn it.
We got a pill?
A full heal, but we don't have any red hearts, so you know.
Whatever.
There's two X's in here!
Wow.
Can't believe it.
Okay, here we go.
Mom!
Oh yeah, you like that?
You like being stuck?
Huh, Mom?
You like being... Oh, that was actually so fucking good!
That was crazy!
Get owned!
Booster pack.
Yep.
Mom's foot.
Soul hearts!
Uh...
Teleport to the... What did that say?
Teleport to the devil or angel?
What about... Okay, hold on.
What about angel rooms?
I haven't seen those in a while.
I think I got to not take devil rooms for that, right?
That was Isaac's red hearts, if Isaac has only one empty heart.
Well, I have none, so that's going to be useless to me.
Mom's foot stumps.
I think I'm going to keep the Joker.
Let's go with Joker.
And we are done on this floor, so...
Sayonara!
Okay, so this is not Mom yet.
We're going to do one, you know, in-betweener, and then we go to the Mom.
Oh, ooh, he almost messed it up there.
Pills!
It's an unidentified!
Okay, that one, I don't remember what it did.
Less useless.
Oh, it wasn't even angel!
It was the other one.
Oh, god.
Oh, yeah, my tears destroyed the...
protectiles!
This is so crazy.
This is going to help me immensely against the heart.
Wait, this is going to take me to three out of three on Leviathan.
But it's going to cost me three blue hearts?
Do it!
What did I get?
Something changed here, maybe?
Ah, wait, this item in itself, what did that do again?
Speed down?
No, thanks.
Oh, wait, I think it gave me extra black hearts.
That's what it did.
For sure.
Because I didn't have that many.
I see now.
I think I want to give this guy coins.
Like, hell yeah.
You can have all my coins.
Except I'm very unlucky.
I'm minus one lock, so this is not going to be a great affair.
Okay, better than nothing.
What's that?
Troll bombs?
Better than what I have.
Give me an eternal heart.
Or a foot.
Hey!
Yes!
Fantastic!
Amazing!
We're going to be pilling so hard from now on.
We're going to hit both.
Pop out, pop out, I dare you, I double dare you.
Well, that was no problem at all.
Whoa, whoa, eight bombs.
Okay, I will spend all my bombs here.
It got converted!
I like it.
I like it a lot.
Pop up, pop up.
Dude, how does this work?
Okay, there you go.
Lovely, lovely, lovely.
Wait, I can spawn a pill in just a second here.
It's going to be a good pill, guaranteed.
I used the wrong button.
Oh, man.
I can't believe I did that.
I found pills?
Wait, that one does what?
No effect.
I found pills.
Okay, fine.
Get those eyes out of here.
Why not?
Oh, there's enemies in here.
Maybe not.
Okay, that's crazy.
Oh god, I can't believe that happened.
What a waste.
I got a slowdown, man.
This is actually the worst throwing ever.
Okay, okay, don't fuck this up now.
Okay, good.
Did you see how I was shooting up there to hit the guy in the bottom?
That was so pro.
Um, okay.
Actually, we should be bombing this.
Damn.
Careful, careful.
Yikes.
Open up, you asshole.
There we go.
So annoying.
What is going on here?
It's a weird room.
Not falling for that.
Very good.
Are there like tinted rocks here at all in these?
Let me have a look here.
I don't see anything out of the ordinary.
Great, more bombs, I need those.
We can make more pills?
Oh, what?
Come on.
Again?
I feel like that's supremely unlucky.
Okay.
So wait, is this... was this the mom one or...
The last one was what?
What did I do last time?
I forgot.
This may be the one before the mom.
Or the heart, I mean.
I'm not gonna fall for that poop.
Not today.
Not falling for it!
It almost got me.
Unbelievable.
Oi!
Sick.
Uh, let's not go in here.
Well, time for the boss.
Wish me luck.
What did this thing do again?
50% chance to gain additional scent.
Right, okay.
Money's kinda useless for me right now.
Okay, it's not mom yet.
A lowkey.
I like when you shoot at me.
Because I can just destroy your projectiles.
Synth oil, more damage.
I mean, that's just gonna sabotage my range, right?
It's backwards range because of the mirror, right?
It's reflecting it.
That is such a troll.
Oh wait, I guess there's no secrets in here.
Ah!
Move on.
Hold on, I need to get a sap of water here.
Did I say sap?
I meant sip?
Okay.
Oh god!
Yeah, that's what I feared would happen.
I'm in big shit here.
Wow.
Okay, okay.
You know what, let's find the heart and get it over with.
This is not... Okay, we see where it is.
We're going there immediately.
I feel like I'm pushing it a little here, you know?
Shit, which is the right way though?
Oh my god.
This way?
No, not that way, huh?
Wait, how am I gonna get there?
It's gotta be via this room then.
Which is almost unbelievable.
Jesus Christ.
Bro, what is it with the no effect pills?
I found pills.
Okay, lock up, that's a little too late though.
Hey, yo, yo.
Oh no.
I got hit from behind.
20% chance to inflict burn on an enemy.
I think it's better than what I have, honestly.
Dude, I'm dying here.
We gotta get to this boss so fast.
We're blowing this up.
Wait, what?
Let me keep blowing it up, actually.
There we go.
That makes me feel better.
What was that?
Charms?
Oh, we're gonna save that for the boss?
Even though it's... Wait, how do I get to this freaking boss room though?
Huh?
Something's off here.
Well, guess I'm going in here.
Another one of these.
That's massive!
Huge!
Unidentified!
No, it's lock up, okay.
Wait, this one is unidentified.
Tears up, nice.
Lock up and...
pheromones, that's the one I had.
What a room though, what a room.
That was great.
Now we're going... Yeah, well, I don't know where we're going.
Oh, it's probably gonna connect from here, right?
Actually, yeah.
Lovely.
This way.
Where are you?
There you are.
Dude, I really like the attack that goes behind me as well.
It's unexpectedly really useful.
Wow!
We got him.
What an obscure path to the boss.
Open up!
Spawns a large puddle of creep.
Ooh, that could actually... Oh, we also have this ready.
What was that?
Another pheromone!
Aw, man.
I think the lemon party may be better for me.
We're gonna put it right in the center of the damn room.
Or actually, right up top, right?
But wait, the part is hanging from the ceiling.
Maybe it's not gonna do much.
Umm...
We're gonna try.
I'm looking for suspicious rocks.
Honestly, this guy looks a little off-color.
Okay, never mind.
It hit me!
Alright, here we go, here we go.
Uh, wish me... Oh, there's a pill back there.
I don't want that pill, actually.
Okay, are we ready?
Are we ready?
Check, check, mic check, lemon party.
Let's do this.
We're going hard.
Wish me luck.
Lemon party for everyone.
Yes, yes, yes.
There, no problem.
No problem.
Absolutely no problem.
We, we got it easy.
Easy, easy.
Uh, wait, I'm not gonna open that yet.
Yes.
Hahaha!
We're going down, baby!
We're going down.
Down into hell!
It lives.
Blue bomber?
Bone and streak?
Oh, what the f- why- Pokemans!
Is burning!
What the fuck?
We unlocked a lot of shit!
What the hell?
Alright.
Uh, well, we know where the boss is.
We're gonna go straight there, dude.
Because I don't have a lot of HP.
This is not looking great, actually.
This may have been a mistake going deeper here.
Oh god.
Alright, alright.
Uh, let me look for rocks!
I don't see anything.
Wait, the boss is right here!
No, oh wait, that's not the boss.
I'm an idiot, the boss is down in the right.
Let's check this out, though.
Ah, should I?
Yeah, we should, we should, we should.
It's no problem.
We're chilling.
Yeah, no problem.
Let's go to the boss.
So I guess that would be going south.
More pills, we love it.
Except that one is horrible.
Uh, let's not go in there.
That's right, fly into the fire, dumbass.
Okay, hold on, I need to try something here.
Ah!
Ah ha!
Hold on now.
Um, now the question is, how do I want to spend my, oh wait.
Wait, how is that good?
How is that a good pill?
That's a bad pill!
I thought all my pills were good now.
Uh, let me wait until I can have more than one.
Oh, here's the boss!
Uh, wait, wait, so hold on.
I forgot how this boss, where I'm gonna get my ass kicked.
I think this may be the end.
We'll see, we'll see how it goes.
Wish me luck, it's Satan!
Ah!
How does it work?
Right?
You do that, that's cool, that's cool.
Oh god.
Okay, okay.
Yeah, I'm already very low HP.
It's not looking good!
Oi, oi, oi.
Yeah, I think it's done.
We're done here.
Oh, the laser!
Not the laser!
Oh, whatever.
Ah, RIP.
Ribarino.
Okay.
Well, that was a fantastic warm-up, though.
You can't say that wasn't a fantastic warm-up.
So, hold on a minute, I unlocked a bunch of shit.
I need to see this.
Wait.
Oh, wait, is it the other order, or...
Okay, I have no idea what I unlocked.
Whatever.
I wish it would show me the latest.
Uh, did I unlock a character?
Samson, Eve...
This one we gotta try.
Judas, Cain, Magdalene... Yeah.
Let's try this one.
Question mark.
The poop.
What is this?
Why are you...
blue?
Okay.
What else do I have?
Oh, crap.
It's so weird not having the laser again.
Like, when you have become used to...
Oh, my God.
Fuck me.
Oh, shit.
Uh, let's go in here.
What's that?
Holy water?
Yeah, it is!
Haha!
That's exactly what it is.
Familiar that charges in the direction Isaac is firing.
Shatters upon hitting an enemy, dealing damage, and spawning a pool of creep that petrifies enemies.
That sounds crazy.
Wait a minute.
Shatters upon hitting an enemy, dealing damage, and spawning a pool...
Okay.
Petrifies.
I like that.
Oh, wait, is it a random chance, or...
Maybe it's... Every time it's reset, so now it's reset.
I see.
Okay.
Oh, my God, it's crazy!
That seems really good.
Also, I have zero bombs, I got one coin, that's about it.
One key now.
Oh, I should... Oi, oi, oi.
Oh, wait, I shattered the thing!
Ah, of course, because it's once per room, I guess.
Yeah, that makes sense.
Okay, let's poop a bit.
I missed.
That's right.
Okay.
No suspicious rocks.
Not that it matters, I have no bombs.
Oh, it's so good!
The holy water!
Oh, I can't reach these.
What a tragedy.
Wait, I'm not done here.
I gotta find bombs.
Also gotta get used to the fact that I'm not flying anymore.
Shit!
Ah, what a...
Jesus.
Dude, I have only blue hearts.
This is a problem.
Okay, that's good.
I like that.
I have two coins.
Please don't hit me.
Okay.
Ah, I can't even buy it!
No!
Wait, the ultimate poop.
Ah, shit.
What a bummer, man.
Also, this character is the one from the cinematic we watched.
Where he looked at me and went, you know?
Famine.
Bosses do not get petrified.
This is not okay.
Oh, man!
I'm seeing a suspicious rock as well, but I can't destroy it.
It is such a tragedy.
Also, I think we're about to die here, like this is close to being the end.
Yeah, that's it.
Okay, we gotta try that again.
We start with three blue hearts every time.
That's really rough!
Like, that is crazy bad.
This is horrible.
How's the damage, though?
3.6?
I mean, that's standard.
Oh, God.
It's not going there.
That's a bad idea.
Oh, hey!
Good start, good start.
Yeah, stepping is out of the question with blue hearts.
What's that?
I've seen that before.
Immurity to explosions, baby!
That's huge.
Now I just gotta stay alive and actually get some use out of it.
Hey, dude.
Get blown up.
We got pills and cards.
Eating pills and playing cards.
Wait, why are so many flies?
Is it just the poop I'm spawning?
This is a lot of flies I have here.
So you want money?
I don't give you money, not yet.
Pop out, friends.
I can't believe that.
Oh, that was close.
Come on, come on.
Dude, really?
He fucking pre-shot that before I came around the corner.
Unreal.
Dreamcatcher.
Oh, this one.
Oh, this may be good for me.
One extra soul heart at the start of each new floor?
Yes, please.
I need soul hearts bad.
In fact, I need red hearts bad.
Give me red hearts, please.
Soul hearts is like...
red hearts is...
black hearts is...
Eternal hearts is...
Right?
That's the levels we're dealing with here.
Another blue fly for me.
Oh, this is going to be...
annoying.
Hello?
I'm Mrs. Hazel.
This is horrible.
Once you go as Hazel, you never go back, baby.
I got five bombs.
I can definitely go a little bit nuts here.
Okay, that's fine.
Useless pills.
I thought these guys spawned the skeletons when they died, but maybe that's another version of them.
No suspicious rocks.
I forgot to pick up the pill.
Oh, my God.
Oh, man, even the simplest room are a challenge.
At least I'm getting a lot of flies.
Maybe that's like...
the whole deal with this guy.
You know, every time you destroy a poop, there's a guaranteed fly in there, no matter what.
That's what it feels like.
Okay.
Let's go.
We got a lot of flies for this one.
In fact, this is the guy that killed me last time, wasn't it?
Too bad these flies don't become my friends.
Oh, God.
If I can beat him, we're gonna get an extra soul heart at the start of next floor.
Okay, I like this.
Keep going like that.
Nice.
A cube of meat.
I'll take it.
Yeah, let's just go.
Wait, we had a pill.
Let's go check out the pill.
In fact, there's two pills.
Friends till the end.
Okay.
And what is this?
Oh, okay.
We also have another pill.
I'm gonna go grab that.
The more pills, the better.
And sus rocks.
We have none.
Oh, I could...
Actually, let's donate a little bit.
If we get lucky.
We didn't get lucky.
Time to die.
Ah, it's hidden behind.
Okay, that's fine.
Still got one bomb.
I got three bombs now.
Let's take this.
The lovers?
Two red hearts.
Well, I'll hang on to that, I guess.
In case I get some more HP.
But we're gonna get another blue heart now.
On the next floor.
And we get to see what bosses is, right?
Because we got the dream thingy.
Let's keep... let's pay attention.
So, what is it?
He's dreaming about...
Uh...
Monstro?
I don't know what that is.
We got half a blue heart!
It's not even a full weight.
Fucking lies!
It says Grant plus one.
That's not plus one.
That's plus a half.
Fucking liars.
I can't believe it!
What's going on here?
Kill him.
Wait, that wasn't too bad!
Um...
Yeah, I'll go in here.
Alright!
Man, all these hearts.
That I can't use.
Oh, I'm gonna be in trouble here.
Actually, it went pretty well.
Hey, not bad.
Okay.
Oh, this is the room for me.
You know what?
Let's save it.
Until we get to the boss, we're gonna go in there and spawn a bunch of flies.
This is the plan.
I'm using every single advantage I can get here.
Because I've been born with a disability called this character.
Answers.
I like that.
Oh, cool.
Let's see.
Aha!
We got a secret up there.
We have only one key, so let's see.
I'm gonna use it on...
Oh, shit.
These guys are gonna jump.
I think.
Nope, they're not gonna jump.
Oh, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait!
This is what was revealed in the dream!
Robo baby!
This is what I saw in the dream, and then I saw something else after.
Wait, is that what it does?
The next...
Oh, yeah!
Next treasure room and boss!
Right.
It's all making sense.
Very good.
Now I have no keys, though, so I can't go in there.
Not that I want to.
I'm poor.
Get him!
I feel like the Robo baby is not that dramatically nice.
Okay.
Let's go around to get to the secret room.
I mean, shooting through opticals, though, is kinda nice.
Hard to aim with it.
Any sus rocks?
Nope.
We can take care of the small ones first before we aggro the big spider.
This is the strategy.
And now we can start to fade him.
He's gonna keep jumping.
Okay, good.
Oh, I forgot to go to the secret room.
Mistakes were made.
Solar!
That is a massive card.
Love that.
Let's go here.
Eternal heart!
You know what we're gonna do, then?
Hey!
But not yet.
So the boss is here, which means we're going to go on a poop adventure now.
We get all the poop we can.
Also that one.
Spawn all the flies in the world.
I need you guys.
We're gonna mobilize an army here.
Look at all these flies.
This is gonna be nice.
It's Monstro!
What a monstrosity.
I almost got hit there.
Oh god!
I mean, I'm just gonna sit at range and laser him.
I'm chilling.
Oh, he's coming.
Okay, time to get out of there.
Okay, let's just keep moving around.
Good.
Solid gameplay here.
Nice!
Doesn't get more beautiful than that, ladies and gentlemen.
And we got speed.
Haha!
You want me to sacrifice stuff?
Okay, a shovel, though?
Ah, a shovel I will maybe sacrifice for.
You're tempting me!
I think I have to do it.
I gotta take it.
Also, I wonder, so I don't have any red hearts, right?
So I wonder if the game recognizes that and is like, okay, so we're not even gonna put a red heart deal for you.
I think that's what's happening.
So I'm gonna take this.
Fuck the poop.
The poop was good, but not anymore.
There's also another secret room we gotta get and the Eternal Heart.
But first, the other secret room.
And look for exes in Texas.
This is very important.
Last bomb.
Okay.
Ah, why not?
Didn't do nothing.
Roger that.
I still get blue flies, so it looks like it's not related to the poop.
It's actually something that is innate to this character.
I'm looking for exes, no exes.
Wait, what's that?
A bomb, okay.
Um, I don't know what I should be doing.
I have three coins.
I could go to the shop just to have a peek.
Ah, no I can't, because I don't have any keys.
So I think we're just leaving.
Yike!
That is so massive.
Like, that is pretty much life-changing for me right now.
Let's go.
Huh?
It generated a blue heart instead!
All right, I guess we're going blue.
This is the ultimate blue experience, I understand.
I get it, I get it.
Fine.
That's okay.
At least we have a nice house, and a beautiful wife, and an expensive car.
No, wait, that's a different song.
No, is it?
That's that song, isn't it?
There's two songs with expensive wives and beautiful homes and houses.
This guy's annoying.
Bro, really?
Finally.
Look for access.
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
How am I gonna...
Hey, la-la-la-la-la-la-la!
This is crazy, this is crazy.
ProGamer here!
I didn't get hit once, that's crazy.
Uh-oh.
I was afraid of a laser there.
Yeah, we can go sideways, though.
Okay, we got no bombs still, which is really sad.
It makes me cry.
Don't you dare!
Oh, God, get out of there.
Oi, yoi, yoi.
Alfredo.
We could go for boss, but I'm gonna say no to that.
Okay.
Boom!
That sounds fun.
Don't have money, though.
Hashtag poor.
What a sad feel.
Oh, thank God it's not laser.
That's just... I'm happy about that.
No laser makes me a happy boy.
Money!
I'm not going back to the shop until I have a lot of money.
That was solid.
Oh, God.
Let's long-range this guy.
We got a guy right here, but no bomb.
Guy spotted, bomb, not had.
In theaters this summer.
Twice!
In a row I got hit.
Three times!
I'm throwing.
It's actually over.
Get him!
Dude, this is crazy.
This room is gonna kill me.
No!
It's over!
How the fuck are you supposed to dodge this shit?
One down.
Oh!
Wow.
Wow, wow, wow.
Ah, should I even go in here?
I feel like...
Actually, we can take a look.
Two boxes.
Man, I'm tempted, but I'm actually gonna...
I'm gonna say no to that!
Blow this up.
Yeah!
We're going in there.
This is me getting my paycheck going back into Las Vegas, you know?
I got more credit.
New lease on life.
Lease on fun, I should say.
Uh-uh.
I can't believe I missed that.
Please die!
How are you not dead?
Finally.
Uh-oh.
These guys are dangerous as hell.
Actually, if I stay at range, they're not dangerous at all.
Ah, chilling!
Oh, wow.
Huge.
Totally worth.
And bombs.
Oh, that was such a good room.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
Let's look for X's.
Actually, I can't...
So, look at this right here.
Let me try and dig on that.
No way!
All right!
What's that?
Sinus infection, chance to fire boogers tears that stick to enemies and deal...
Yes.
App so lutely signed me up for that one.
Incredible.
Dude, we're gonna need to look for these fucking decorations right now.
We got X's, we got hemorrhoid marks.
I don't know what the next thing is gonna be.
I didn't know what to call it.
It was the first thing I thought of.
Doesn't even make any sense what I just said.
But you know what I mean.
I didn't even see the spikes!
I'm blind.
I'm stuck in a corner!
Crazy room!
Okay, okay, we made it.
We made it barely.
New lease on life.
Now we have to be ultra grateful for every moment we spend alive.
Because it could have been over.
Show me what's good.
Rotten tomato.
Special tears that apply a bait effect.
Slows enemies and draws other nearby enemies to attack them.
Yeah.
That sounds delicious.
It sounds like a good deal.
I take that deal.
You take that deal?
He shot straight!
That's illegal!
They're supposed to shoot fucking spirals.
Liar.
Illegalization here.
Okay, he's gone.
Do we have any more decorations?
Not that I can see.
Also, I need a little bit more mana.
We can get it from the boss.
We have 14 monies.
We should be able to do something in this room over here now.
I can buy a soul heart.
Or I boom.
Big bada boom.
Hmm.
I need this.
I got a plate safe.
Let's buy a card as well.
The magician is good, right?
The magician...
I think it spawns a blue heart.
Increases my damage and something else.
So I'm going to use it against the boss that's difficult.
Yep.
Let's see what boss this is.
No, wait, it's range.
Magician is range.
Yep.
It is indeed...
Oh, it's also homing!
Right, okay.
Very good.
Homing boogers.
That's scary, isn't it?
Bro, will you please just appear so I can damage you?
Oh god, I got hit.
Ah, the boogers are doing work.
Huge.
Is this going to give me a blue heart?
Ah, these bastards.
Take that out, take that out, take that out.
Okay, so what are we...
We have the gimp.
And money equals power.
Grants a small damage up for each co...
I mean...
I can't afford it, man.
I need my HP.
Oh, wait, this is only going to do half of the damage to me, though, right?
Half a damage?
Half a damage.
Fuck!
It did two hearts!
Oh, the run is over now.
If I had known that, I wouldn't do it.
God fucking damn it.
How is that even possible?
Two hearts?
Maximum one, though.
One there and one back, right?
Or half one there, half back.
I don't know why it's suddenly two hearts.
Well, I'm going to go dig again.
Oh, it's okay.
I thought I bought it.
It's okay.
Calm down.
It's all good.
I thought I wasted my money.
It's all right.
Especially now that money equals power, I don't want to be poor.
You know what I need?
I need a converter.
Actually, do I?
Wait, how does a converter work on this character?
Hold on a minute.
How do I convert?
Let me...
Uh-huh.
Why not?
This run is rough.
Two hearts right now.
We should have an extra half heart.
It should have been a full heart, by the way.
But, okay.
I got lied to.
Let's not step on any of that.
Oh, God.
Good.
Jesus.
Yeah, poisoned.
Get boogers.
Now I need to find the one that gives me 99 coins.
Imagine that, dude.
Imagine.
That's fine.
My stats are not that fantastic, actually.
Whoa.
Money!
We love to see it.
That's a decent amount of extra damage we're getting out of that.
I expected it to be worse.
That is a good amount.
I can't hit anything.
I need more shot speed or tier, so I can apply more boogers.
This is what's gonna catapult me into greatness.
And we can't spend any money.
Look for floor decorations.
What constitutes floor decoration?
I feel like it's gotta be super obvious.
I feel like this grass is not a floor decoration, for example.
I'll keep an eye out.
I don't see anything suspicious in here.
Oh, yes, money me.
Money me.
Give me that damage.
These guys are dangerous.
Hey, yo, yo.
Scary.
Yeah, these guys are gonna fuck me.
I'm just gonna long-range these guys.
Yeah, play it safe.
Nothing suspicious in here.
Holy shit.
Good.
Look for stuff on the floor.
I'm not seeing anything obvious.
Oh, he's burning.
No, he's bleeding.
That's what's happening.
Okay, he's gonna bleed for a while.
Let's move around.
Not bad.
Playing is strategic.
Bro, I have such trouble hitting these guys.
I need more tears.
I shoot so slow.
Oh, my God!
There's more and more enemies!
Please die!
Fucking hell.
What a room.
Looking for axes.
And hemorrhoids.
I don't see any.
Maybe the hemorrhoids are only in the fight rooms.
Nice.
We like the boogers.
Boogers are delicious.
I could go in there.
Should I?
Let's... not yet.
We gotta look for an axe.
Or similar.
Kill him.
Yeah, we take care of the small guys first.
You're stuck back there, huh?
Totally worth.
The safety this gives me.
You gotta use every advantage.
Nice.
Item room, please be good to me.
What's that?
Lord Sid... hold on.
Uh...
A chance to fire a sit-shot that deals 2x Isaac's damage and spawns a pool of slowing white creep.
You know what I need with this build right here?
I need luck.
Because I have so many things that rely on luck.
Actually, maybe this one doesn't, but...
A lot of the stuff I have is luck.
I need that and tears.
Taking damage also launches a sit.
That's... no relevance.
Okay.
I'll take it.
We need luck and tears.
Two blue hearts.
This is so... it's rough.
How about you give me that flying that I get on every single Azazel run, huh?
I'm gonna get hit here.
Maybe.
Uh-oh.
Oh my god.
Yes, good damage, good damage.
Okay, okay, that's fine.
Okay, that wasn't too bad at all!
Cat of Nine Tails, yes.
Very good, very good, very good, very good.
Um, no special rooms.
Did I miss something?
Wait, we have 23 coins.
That shop, that wasn't a real shop, right?
That was a...
That was a greed, wasn't it?
Let me go back.
Oh, wait a minute.
Okay.
Yeah, let's go in there.
Let me go to the shop.
Maybe there's somewhere we can dig.
I don't wanna waste this dig, you know?
Like, there's gotta be some place I can put the dig.
Maybe down here.
I almost got hit by that.
I don't see anything, but let's start bombing.
I should have done it here.
It's probably there.
Ah, okay.
I can't enter here, unfortunately.
I'm pretty sure there's a hemorrhoid in there.
That I could use.
Let's see.
Is there anything special in here?
Should we just try to dig?
Dude!
Let's try and dig in here.
I'm gonna dig on these papers.
Hey!
Wait, really?
Maybe it's just completely random.
Maybe it doesn't matter where I dig.
No fucking way.
Gopi's tail.
Increases chance of chests as room clear rewards, but also increases chance of...
This one sounds so bad!
Like, this is net negative!
I'm gonna take it.
We'll see if it's actually good or not.
You see that cursed question mark?
Like, should we take this?
That's horrible!
Let me see.
Like, there's gotta be a fucking upside to this.
Increases chance of chests as room clear rewards, but also increases chance of...
Yeah.
This is gonna even out to be shit.
Depends on the percentages here.
Like, this could be super horrible or super good depending on the percentages.
I'm in the black here, I know nothing.
Okay, we're getting out.
This way.
Hey!
Oh!
Time thingy and we're dealing with...
Devil Boy.
Time thing and Devil Boy?
A Golden Snake!
I've never seen anything like this.
Oh, they dropped money!
Oh, that's huge for me!
I need them to die over land so I can actually get the money.
Hell yeah!
Money is power is gonna be my saviour this run.
Uh oh.
Rosary bead?
Wait, faith up.
Oh god, it's laser boys!
We're chilling, we're chilling.
Stay at range.
Okay, good.
Brother!
I'm losing too much HP here.
Oh no.
This was not good.
We lost the whole heart.
Phew!
Wait, let's see if we can dig in here.
Yeah!
Wait, there's an X and triangles?
Let's do X.
Yeah!
Yeah, question mark, okay.
We have an invisible guy in here?
Okay, I don't know if that's a thing.
Stompy, oh wait, that's a good one.
Isaac can break most.
Yes!
That's the one.
That's a good one.
I gotta be careful though.
Let's try not to walk on rocks with bombs in them.
That could be a problem.
Really keep an eye out for that.
Oh!
And that!
Yeah, we gotta keep an eye out for everything.
Suck on it.
Oh no.
That's so evil I couldn't escape!
Did you see that?
Like, I couldn't move out of the laser.
Like, they got me knocked up.
I didn't mean to say that, I don't know why I said that.
Right, we knew that was going to be the hourglass.
That was the one that rewinds.
But there's no time to rewind time!
If I get hit, it's over.
So this is actually completely useless.
I'll take the shovel, thank you.
Like, this run is pretty much over.
Yeah.
That's a rough one.
Oh, I didn't mean to restart.
Okay, we do one more.
We do one more with the fucking shitty character here.
The poop character.
Because he's literally poop.
Like, the worst character in the game so far.
It may even be worse than Judas.
At least Judas has a red heart.
Not that the red heart is worth much.
Because you only have one, but still.
Actually, I would say they're probably equal.
In shittiness.
I feel like this guy has a bit more damage, actually.
Yeah, spawn the flies for me.
The worst item in the entire game.
I don't even want it.
Fuck that.
You can piss off.
Let's go in here.
Okay.
I am gonna go south to the warm lands.
Oh, no.
Okay, good.
Oh, almost got hit there.
Can I distract them with poop?
Get distracted, nerd.
Finally!
Nice!
There's probably someone I can distract with poop.
What about the poop monster?
The poop boss?
God, I'm saying poop a lot when I play this game.
The poop per hour is off the charts.
Oh, wait, this is actually totally fine.
Hey, I thought it came back for me.
This is a horrible room.
Oh, it's not, it's not.
I need a bomb, though.
I saw tinted rock, I saw it.
I'll be back, maybe.
Give me money.
That sounds really good.
But 15?
Ain't nobody got money for that.
That's a floor decoration.
Right there, you see that?
Blighted ovum.
This one's dangerous.
I'm probably gonna take a little bit of damage.
Yeah, I knew it.
I always take damage from that little fucker.
I hate it.
It's almost the first shot, and then I'm okay after, you know?
Every time.
Totally unnecessary there.
HP for me.
Oh, yeah, it's the blue HP.
It's so bad.
We're taking no deals this run.
This is a no deal.
We're keeping all the hearts to ourself.
No deal.
You know, that's a TV show deal, no deal.
I don't know, maybe that's only in Denmark we had that.
Well, that's what you would say, you know?
Sure.
Wow!
Dude!
Okay.
You know how hard I worked for that half a heart?
Okay, that's good.
Money.
No bombs.
Shit.
Oh, not this guy!
I'll see you guys in 15 minutes.
There goes my massive item I just received before.
Out the window, just like that, flushed.
The least you could do is reveal a secret to me there.
Not even that, I guess.
Hey, this is the same poop room we had earlier.
You know what, I'm actually kind of happy I'm playing this character.
Because I feel like there's got to be something with it, right?
So, for example, in the cutscene, this guy was prominent.
I mean, we probably unlock some bullshit if we beat the game with this character, you know?
Just like the other characters.
Like some of them actually unlock other characters if you don't die, you know, like Lazarus.
Wait, what's seven?
Oh, this one.
Okay, go north.
Uh, that's actually kind of annoying, because I can't get in there.
Oh, what a blue ball.
For a blue boy.
Lost contact.
I guess that's good.
I'll take anything at this point.
Do I use my last key here?
I do.
Do I gamble everything?
I take this.
Whenever you see Blue Heart as the blue boy, we take it.
It's a very simple ruleset we're following here.
The flowchart has never been simpler.
I need you guys to jump out at me.
Can you do that for me?
I thought these guys could jump.
Maybe those are the other spiders.
Okay.
We take all the flies we can get as well.
Nice.
Matchstick!
A chance of fighting bombs!
That's massive for me!
Because I am in a huge bomb shortage.
Money is good as well.
Uh-oh.
Oh man, those spiders really helped me out there.
Definitely eating the pill.
Great.
I knew what I was getting myself into.
I can't complain about that.
We got the butterflies.
I feel like this is an upgraded version of this boss.
Like he's way more flyy than normal.
Right?
Like this is not normal.
I barely have time to attack him.
Yeah, this is not a normal Duke of Flies.
This is Nuke of Flies.
Some damage in there.
Like he's protected by the flies.
Yeah!
Wow!
Hey, you like poop?
Go to the poop!
I thought at least they would be attracted to the poop.
Isn't that what flies do?
Dude, Nuke of Flies got a hands.
We ain't done yet.
If I take damage now, I will delete the game.
And never come back.
Okay.
We got tears and range back.
Good stuff.
Random heart pickups, please be blue.
Okay, I'll take that.
That's nice.
Better than nothing.
I'm not even gonna go in there, guys.
I am saying no deal today.
If anything, I'm betting on angels to take my hand and carry me to the Promised Land.
It's just...
I hate when I cover Duke's items!
It's impossible.
This is insane!
I just don't have the damage here!
I feel underpowered.
Okay, I have massive range.
I really should be using that to my advantage.
This is my strength.
Bombs?
Good.
I need way more of that.
You've got to be kidding me!
All this hard-earned HP is just going out the window and it breaks my heart.
Okay, give me that.
I'm yet to find an amazing heart.
I think this may be the end of me, guys.
This room is gonna kill me.
Okay, good.
Take care of this guy.
Utilize the range.
Good.
I can't even kill them when they pop up.
That's how little damage I have.
Yeah, you like that range, guys?
Look at that!
The contacts are actually massive.
Are helping a lot.
Wonderful.
Boss is here.
No hearts, unfortunately.
That is so sad.
I'm gambling.
Oh, well.
Could at least have healed my blue hearts, no?
I feel like that is not too much to ask for.
Good.
I want Spider Mod.
Can I please have that?
No treasure room found yet, either.
There it is.
Oh, not these guys again.
What is it with this freaking level here?
They're everywhere.
Okay, one down, one down.
Ah, thank God.
What do we have?
An unknown item.
It's a new one.
It looks like an active.
It hurts.
No, it doesn't.
Taking damage fires a ring of ten large tiers and grants a stacking tier stat bonus for the current room.
These ring tiers leave bloody cre- That sounds fucking horrible.
The last thing I want to do is get hit with this character.
Very bad.
Okay, well, we found the treasure room.
Let's just go to the boss.
I need to find one of those gambling machines that will give me like ten thousand blue hearts.
This is the way to win.
Also, there's just question marks on the character.
So, I don't know what's up with that.
That makes me super intrigued.
Wait, that was- I can't stand on this.
We're gonna jump or...
Oh, you're spawning one of these.
I have such bad DPS, though.
Oh.
He's gonna spawn another one soon, I think.
Two maximum.
Yeah, there it is.
We're on the clock.
Oh, I got hit at the end.
It was so good until it wasn't.
Oh well.
We got one heart out of it.
One meager heart.
So bad.
You pretty much can't take damage on this character.
Like, this is just how it works.
Eat it.
Oh no, not again!
Fuck, man!
Fuck these characters!
I hate it to no end!
Don't run into that.
He's spawning flies now.
Fuck!
Oh my god, he moves faster, too.
Oh my god!
Oh man!
It's over.
I can't do this.
Can we slow down a bit?
I have no damage!
There's no damage on this character.
Whoa.
Focus.
What the shit, man?
Half a heart.
I may as well just restart.
Or just die on purpose or whatever.
What's the point, even?
Oh no.
Yeah, kill me.
Get me the fuck out of here.
Alright, we're doing this character all day.
Huh?
This is fine.
I've stopped questioning this game.
I'm just saying whatever.
Sure.
Here's some poop for you.
And these guys can't die.
We got new music, too.
Okay, they're down, so not only this guy.
Alright, you start with nothing.
You don't even have any bombs or anything on this character, man.
Oh, what the hell?
Everyone's on fire!
Cool soundtrack, though.
I'm a fan of that.
Of course.
Oh, that is massive, actually.
Wow.
I am so unbelievably grateful for that blue heart.
You know what?
Since we're so early, I think it's a good idea.
Oh, fuck.
I thought you were charging.
You weren't whistling!
Okay, man.
Just end it all.
Like, just end my life right now, man.
Am I crazy, or does this character have, like, zero damage?
There's nothing good about this character.
No redeeming qualities whatsoever.
Okay.
We got him.
Pentagram, increase... Damage!
Huh?
Fuck off.
I'm not leaving until I get my treasure.
Give me my treasure.
Come on.
Just... I'm not even gonna get close... No!
I wait for you!
Come on!
I'm not going over there.
Thank you.
With all these stones, it's gotta be, like, something...
sauce about it.
There's one there.
Awesome.
Actually huge.
This is the best start I've had so far.
This is free, right?
Yeah, it's open.
Give me coins.
I'm gonna buy that heart in there.
Dude, this soundtrack slaps hard.
This is really nice.
Proptosis... Damaged.
Here's gain a large damage bonus, but I've much shorter range.
It says large damage bonus.
I wouldn't say 0.7 is large.
Let's see.
It's not that bad, I guess.
The bigger size is gonna help me in close quarters.
I'm just gonna need to get some range.
I mean...
That shouldn't be too hard to get, right?
I feel like range is relatively common.
Whereas damage is a little more rare to get.
Burning basement 2.
I wonder if this counts as a decoration right here, the little drawing.
Or maybe the burn marks.
Oh my god, this is gonna...
Okay, the damage is good!
Damage is good.
Houston, the damage is wonderful.
That's gonna help me.
I think there's extra damage that I'm not seeing reflected in my stats, depending on the range here.
Because that's more damage, for sure, than what my UI is showing.
Okay.
You're not even gonna stop moving, huh?
I gotta get in close.
Oh man, oh man.
Oh, it's not that bad, actually.
What a weird room.
Oh yeah, definitely.
Like, when they're right next to me, they take so much damage.
Oh man, this soundtrack is so good!
Maybe one of my favorites.
Not my ultimate favorite, but one of them right now.
Recency bias plays a factor as well.
Okay, well...
Can I have flying, please?
Will the RNG gods be so willing?
Terrible.
Oh, I one shot him.
Because I was so close.
Wait, we haven't even found treasure room.
Huh?
Oh, my flies killed him.
Very nice.
Yes, definitely buying that.
Thank you.
This is the best start we've had.
No doubt about it.
Ah, no.
I mean, yes.
What's that?
Eight inch nails.
Oh!
Cool.
More damage, replaces tears with nails that have increased knockback.
Wait a minute, how does it work with the...
Oh, the sizes do get smaller still, okay.
I like that, knockback is good for me.
Get them out of my face, right?
Steven!
Hello?
Sup, Steven?
Let's crack a wagon.
Oh, man.
Little Steven has appeared.
Well, okay.
Is that Little Steven?
No, that's Steven.
More damage up.
Straight up just damage up.
All right.
We're not going in.
Also, look at my angel meter.
36.2%.
I want to see angels again, Gandalf.
Angels!
Yeah, no, I got no keys.
We're doing this.
Kimi, Kimi, no keys.
You got to get in up close and personal here.
Huge.
That was beautifully played.
I can say that.
Oh, I don't see the map, huh?
Okay.
Is this going to be a little questionable then?
Now I just need some keys.
Can I move these?
No.
Oh, that was bad.
That was bad.
I shouldn't have done that.
I feel like a fighter plane diving in and dropping the bomb and going out again, you know?
Exchanging potential energy for kinetic energy.
And then back up to potential energy.
Up and down like a roller coaster.
Energy games.
Wow!
Let's kill this guy.
Look at the aim!
Precision!
Oh wait, I have no map.
Ah, this way then.
Fuck!
Another bomb?
Meow.
Very... this is going swimmingly.
We actually have damage.
When enemies die fast, there's less time for you to take damage.
Dude, I need this key real bad.
I think I can...
Wait, can I?
No.
Maybe with the really precise angle it could go through there diagonally, but it's gotta be like really precise.
Wouldn't mind a shot right now.
Get in there, drop my load and get out.
Oi!
Close one.
Key!
Wonderful.
Uh,
should I go back and... yeah, I think I should go back.
Go back and use the key on... whatever I wanted to use the key on, I forgot what that was.
I am so lost.
It was not that one.
Or maybe it was?
But I mean, 20 gold?
I gotta go in there.
But wait a minute.
I think it was a treasure room.
Yeah, let's go in here.
Okay, definitely, I think I'm gonna buy that.
Sharp key.
More keys?
Yeah!
Definitely.
Uh, yeah.
Then we're taking that.
Things are looking up.
Let me just confirm here.
So, the key damages and pierces enemies and can also open the first lock or destroy the first obstacle.
That's actually big.
Enemies killed by the key projectile have a chance to drop pickups.
That's also really cool.
I need more keys.
Let's go back and see if we can't find the other room that I wanted to use my key on.
I think it was all the way back here.
Yeah, there it is.
A jalapeno!
Birds eye!
Chance with firing tears to also fire a sliding red flame projectile.
That's very mediocre in my experience.
But better than nothing.
There's nothing in there.
Oh man, you're fast!
These poops are out of control!
Whoa!
Wait, why is this so big?
That's way bigger than it was last time I had this.
Okay, at least I can't take damage from that.
Maybe it's not so bad after all.
Panic button.
Just before taking damage, if charged, automatically use I6 active.
No.
I don't want to use that.
That sounds horrible.
Terrible.
I wonder if the flame is so big, because it synergizes with the contacts or whatever it was.
The short-range thing, so that's... because right when it appears, it's big, right?
And then it becomes smaller, but because the flame is big from the start or something, then it stays like that?
I don't know.
That's my, you know, hand-wavy theory.
Okay, the question is, where do I go now?
Nothing in there.
Man, playing with an old map is just excruciating.
Oh, maybe here.
And this...
Right, I remember this.
But did I move on from here?
Oh, it's a dead end, okay.
That explains a lot!
Here we go.
The fire!
Wish I could fly.
Wait, so should I be...
What if I kill the boss with this key?
With the sharp key?
The finishing blow.
Maybe it gives me, like, an extra item, you know?
I think that could be a cool sort of mechanic.
Oh, god.
Where's my flames?
There we go.
Ooh, that did a lot of damage!
Whoa!
I love the flame!
Ball of bandages.
Angel!
Uh, overall familiar... whatever.
I'm going in, I'm going in.
What am I being blessed with?
Dead sea scrolls, triggers another active item effect, chosen a random...
Maybe I want that?
I mean, okay.
I think it's better than the key thing.
Because I'm not going to be shooting my keys, come on.
I like that I was excited about getting the wig.
Uh, suspicious.
Everything's very dark here.
Oh, yeah, you like that?
Oh, wait, it's over, it's over!
Monster... wait, what is... oh, right, okay.
That's what that did.
At least I can see the map now.
Oh, it's so much more comfortable with damage!
These guys are not that scary anymore.
Battery?
Another battery.
Closed.
Alright.
Fine.
The Book of Sin?
I think that's damage.
Dude, how am I going to kill these guys?
How?
There we go.
Hoi-yoi-yoi.
One shot, one kill.
Two shots, one kill, okay.
Definitely pilling.
Puberty.
So wait, if I get more puberty, I get a heart, I think.
Which is not going to be that much for me, but okay.
Whoa.
Wait, what?
Tractor beam.
Control...
tiers?
Huh?
I need to read that.
Oh, a lot of good stats.
Emits a beam from Isaac's face.
Tears travel within the beam, sinking with Isaac's movement.
No way!
Changing the direction of the beam also instantly...
Holy shit!
Alright, that is awesome.
Huge fan of that.
Damn.
This is freaking cool.
Ah, come here.
I'm running out of HP though, this is getting a little dicey.
Everything dies.
I don't have that much money, but I was hoping for a blue heart.
I'll be back.
Yum heart.
That's the one that heals, so that's useless for me.
Boss, we could do it.
Actually, I'm gonna wait until my active is ready.
At least.
I need one more coin as well.
If I get that, I can go to the shop and buy the chance of getting a blue heart.
Let's go here.
Oh, you know what?
I can do advanced stuff like...
If I do this and then come walking like that, you know?
Oh man, I need to start.
This is actually really good.
Fighter butt?
Oh, they got scared?
I got six bombs, I could maybe try to find a secret.
Too bad.
Maybe here.
Actually, I think I know where there's a secret.
I'm gonna try here and one more in place.
Okay, so it's not here.
Whoa.
I'm not gonna go in there.
You like the flame?
Did the flame just instantly kill him?
That's freaking nuts.
That flame is not to be trifled with.
Okay, so right here.
What?
Okay, then I don't know.
Let's go to the boss.
Saving my remaining bombs.
I do have seven keys, by the way.
I mean, coins.
Fuck.
I was hoping for a blue heart.
Okay, here we go.
Please be a good active.
Enter, kiss, cook.
Oh, bombs.
Dude, that turned out to be really good.
More range?
Not that it... I guess...
Wait.
Let me actually check, so I stand here.
They disappear right after the hatch, and now...
It's about the same, though.
No difference.
We say no to the devil, and we say yes to the angel.
Fun fact, if I had taken any deals, I would have been dead by now.
Because I only have three hearts.
I know it's not as simple as that, the logic, but you know, approximately it is.
Ah, I can get across here.
Advanced strategies.
Oh, that is incredible!
Much needed.
Okay, this is something, isn't it?
Let's do north first.
Oh, that was a nice room.
Ah, well, shit.
It is what it is.
These flies are tanky.
I have a feeling, right here.
Man, I should never trust them.
Why do I keep falling back to trusting my guts?
Oh, I can't believe that happened.
Wait, I needed to go south as well.
I'm so bad.
The fire, though!
Hoi-yoi-yoi.
Alright.
Ah, I keep going south.
Um, yeah, why not?
Okay, that was not worth it.
Tammy's head?
Oh, god.
Nice.
Be good to me.
The pills have not been good to me this run.
That was so bad.
The fires, though, are actually kind of goaded.
Do I take the chance on another pill?
Hmm...
Give me that back.
Keys and bombs.
Oh, I don't like this, actually.
Um...
Not worth it.
Still haven't found treasure...
What is it with me and treasure rooms today?
Like, I find them so late.
Very unlucky.
I almost messed it up again.
Plate safe!
I gotta be waiting just a bit longer there.
Oh, man.
Oh, no.
What the fuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuuck!
Familia, that fire is... I mean, sure.
I need HP, though.
Like, I think we're about to be done here.
Like, this run is about to hit the shitter.
Two hearts, man.
It's not enough!
Also, I don't trust this.
I'm going to have to destroy this again.
Go!
Oh, man.
Close.
Whew.
Now we go... down.
I'm nervous.
This is one... wait, you know what?
Donate the money.
Because I'm going to be dead now anyway.
Just get it in there.
Should I... I'm going to blow it up.
The D4 has appeared in the basement.
Okay.
Four-sided die.
No key.
That's more damage.
That's damage.
We know that.
Not bad.
Speed the... ooh.
Angel power.
Seraphim.
Following the heart, baby!
Thank you!
That's massive.
All right.
Okay.
So what now?
Curse of the maze.
Okay.
I'm not going to stand on that.
There we go.
Oh, god.
Once again, I'm asking for your support in terms of hearts.
Best friend?
Oh, I see him.
He's just lying there.
Any sus rocks?
Nope.
Not that I can see.
That went surprisingly well in there.
Wait, what?
How did he just die?
We got demons!
In the moon!
Oh, okay.
Not that great.
That door is open somewhere.
And I intend to find it.
You best believe it.
Come here.
Oh, that's good.
That's good.
Virgo!
Chance when taking damage to activate a shield for 10 seconds.
Chance increases with luck.
Converts negative picks.
Yes!
It's pill time, baby!
Hell yeah.
Oh, we got evil fires.
Actually, these fires are good.
We got to destroy these fires.
I got one coin.
That's so sad.
Power pill.
Every two enemies killed.
Oh, I didn't know that.
Inflict fear to all enemies.
Isaac can't shoot.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, that's actually good to know.
Power pill also heals me when I kill enemies with it.
That's new knowledge.
Wait!
I can't get to it!
I can't believe I've done this.
Ah, shit.
I'll give this guy a coin.
Please give me some.
Please.
Oh, okay.
I'm gonna fuck you up then.
You're gonna die then.
You're gonna die.
And that's a pill for me.
Pills are good now.
Speed up.
Wonderful.
Okay, we're done here.
Let's go west.
Jesus Christ.
I got a little dicey.
I have so many familiars with me.
That's kind of cool, actually.
Oh, no, I can't believe it.
I got hit.
I can't afford to get hit.
I just can't.
Key for a coin, actually, yeah.
Because it's free.
I got infinite keys.
Lazy worm, what was that?
Less shot speed, more damage.
Eee, no thanks.
I'm good, bruh.
Keep that.
No, thank you.
Oh, wait, wait, what is that blue one there?
Ah, that's the room I couldn't access.
Or, I mean, the boss now.
It's mom and we're gonna use everything we got.
Wish me luck.
It's gonna go horribly.
The nail?
Huh?
Keep doing damage.
We're doing good damage.
Yes!
We fucking killed her!
And we got angel power.
Oh, what's that?
Oh god, these are evil.
Take it!
Holy death shot, what?
What's that?
Seraphim, two out of three, by the way.
Chance to fire holy tears that summon a damaging beam of light upon striking enemy.
Okay.
So, it's like snot, but holy snot.
It's the same idea behind it.
Okay, we got three hearts, better than nothing.
Let's move on.
We gotta find a lot of blue hearts now.
We just gotta find a lot.
It's as simple as that.
I think there to it, we just saw it in action.
The light from above came down.
5% chance when taking damage to destroy the trinket and spawn an item.
That sounds amazing.
I love that.
Oh my god, oh my god!
We somehow deal a lot of damage now.
This is, yep, this is good.
Oh, fuck.
Should I do this?
I'm gonna do this.
Mom's bottle of pills.
Oh, crap.
Wait, I have a shield now.
I know you're gonna jump, I know you're gonna jump, you're gonna jump!
Okay, okay.
Yeah.
That's huge.
Get struck by the light beams.
Oh, man.
I'm not even gonna take the chance here.
Just play it safe.
The hell is this?
Where's the light beams at?
Pills are good.
Aw, it's not... it's... aw, man.
Where's my blue hearts at, though?
I need an inverse converter.
I want to turn red hearts into blue hearts.
Can I have that?
Oh, wait.
This may be... no, it's not good, actually.
That's bad for me, because I want my guys to orbit me and, you know, protect me from all sides.
Aw, I'm not going for that one, am I?
Wait, no.
Look at that!
Who's a god gamer?
Huh?
I think I am.
Not bad.
Okay, so now, let's go here.
Fires are good, lights are good.
Hey, what did I do?
Did I just take damage?
I think I just took damage.
Please, open!
Why are you closed?
Oh.
Antichrist cookbook?
Mom!
Aw, it's so over.
We're so dead.
One HP, yeah, right.
It is so freaking over.
I hate it, man.
Like, can I just find some goddamn blue hearts?
I feel like I find a million of them in any other run, you know?
But when I need them, I see none.
Fucking crazy.
Oh, man.
Yeah, give me blue hearts.
Wait.
Nope.
Absolutely not.
Huh?
I don't even know how I died.
I'm going again.
I'm too stubborn here.
We're just going again and again and again.
It's all... Honestly, at this point, I feel like it's all about luck.
Like, it's...
Do I find blue hearts or not, you know?
And I just didn't find any blue hearts, so, you know, what can you do?
Not a lot.
Oh, he actually gets affected when he walks through the fire.
This is the most useless item in the entirety of the universe, so I'm not even going to pick it up.
This is my protest.
What's that?
Good one.
But I guess it does damage enemies, right?
Oh, I may as well take it.
Except I can't.
I could if I use a bomb.
Yeah, why not?
I wanted to distract enemies.
I've got no keys.
How much do you want to bet I'm not even going to find a single key?
It's just one of those things, you know?
You'll see.
Maybe here?
Crap.
There's a key.
Oh, but we gotta be precise.
Yeah, I'm going for the coin.
They called me crazy.
Not
bad.
The Bible is actually amazing.
Yeah, I mean, it's Bible.
It's Bible.
We're going full God mode.
Yeah, time for the boss.
No bombs, unfortunately.
Oh, actually, maybe I should use my flight here.
Actually, yeah.
We take this, we take that.
Okay, not bad.
Hey, I feel like I've gotten this boss like three times in a row on the first floor.
Is that just me?
Also, I'm just taking a million damage here for no reason.
Oh, God, he's doing that now.
Ah, piss off!
I'm so tilted now.
For fuck's sake, I'm at one HP.
I may as well quit the game, dude.
I hate this boss.
Burning basement too.
We got fight, so we take it.
Sure.
Cancer?
I can't see anything.
And Jackie is at my feet doing things.
It's really distracting right now.
Oh, what the hell, man?
What is up with that?
I'm not going to heal my wounds, but it's getting there at least.
The good news here is that the music is good, and that's keeping me going here.
Because this is miserable.
You see, you know what?
This should be a challenge.
Like, this character should be in the challenges section.
Because this is a fucking challenge playing with blue arts.
Why is this not a challenge, you know?
I feel like it's miscategorized here.
At least we got some money.
No key!
Damn.
We're not going to find one, are we?
The guitar riff!
There it is, baby!
The luck is with us.
The good news is we have the Bible against Mom.
Explosivo, 25% chance to fire a sticky tear that will grow and explode for 60...
I feel like this is going to bite me in the ass, man.
It's an upgrade though, right?
I take it.
I just got to not stay next to the enemy, I guess.
Maximum rage play.
Range play.
And rage play, both.
Let's go left.
Yeah, that's scary.
Like, when they jump towards me, when they have the bomb on them, not good.
Like that!
Ah, just fucking end my life already.
Kill that thing.
Please give me some blue hearts.
Steven, you know what?
Here's a Bible for you!
Be banished!
Okay, you don't care about the Bible?
That's cool.
Here, bombs on you.
Okay, I mean, I'm actually kind of glad.
Just fucking start this shit over.
No.
I wonder if one button is bad.
Is it always going to be the second button bad, too?
There's a third button.
Thanks.
A party hat.
Bozo, damage.
One soul hot.
Oh, you're so generous!
Random chance to briefly apply fear or charms on enemy.
Just spawn a rainbow poop.
Yeah, whatever the fuck rainbow poop means.
Who knows?
The fucking mystery, man.
Nobody in the universe knows what that does.
It's just a slightly more delightful poop, you know?
That's what that is.
Either that or a gay poop.
One or the other.
Come here, guys.
There we go.
I like the party hat.
Running around.
You see that face?
That's me in real life right now.
This is how I look right now.
Gimme.
Come here, son.
Did I find a treasure room?
I don't remember.
These runs are all flooding together in my mind.
I did, okay.
No keys, though.
Okay.
Guess we're doing the boss.
I'm gonna poop in his face and maybe he will be distracted.
It's this guy again!
What are the chances?
I don't fucking believe it!
Time to lose two hearts.
Dude!
He is next... like, this guy is harder than mom.
And it's the first level.
Kill me!
Fucking kill me.
Just take me out, dude.
Here, let me help.
Ah, kill me.
Kill me.
Kill me!
I lost some heart.
We can't win anything.
We gotta remain at three hearts.
Kidney bean.
Fear that... whatever.
I feel like charm is useless.
Because you can't rely on it.
Sometimes they are charmed and they still throw bombs or attack me or something.
It is very inconsistent.
Just like their movement.
It's the exact same.
Kill me!
Take me out.
This is the only way to win, man.
Nothing to lose anyway, right?
Okay.
I'm just letting you know right now.
If I end up winning with this character and I don't get anything from it, I may actually just burn all my books.
For no reason at all, it's just...
I feel like punishing myself or subjecting myself to this.
That was a close one there.
Is the music reacting to what I'm doing?
It sounds like it.
Close quarters with jumping jacks.
It's not gonna end well, is it?
Happy ending!
Just go for it.
We're fucking speedrunning this now.
New plan.
We're speedrunning.
Here.
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on.
Yeah, kill me.
Just kill me.
Next!
Kill me!
Thank you.
If I don't get brimstone or flying within the first approximate 78 seconds, I will die on purpose.
Nice.
We got a finger?
What the hell is that?
It's just a finger.
It's a familiar.
It deals damage.
Oh, right.
I remember this, actually.
I've had this before.
It's kind of funny.
Nobody likes getting pointed at.
It deals like no damage, though, so it's pretty much useless.
I guess it's good at keeping some enemies at bay, you know?
Some enemies, they reduce in size when they take damage.
And you can keep them in bay like that.
Or at bay.
Oh, it's really going to destroy fires.
Whoa.
Holy shit.
Well, they learned.
Well, I can't afford anything.
Finally, we got a different boss.
I can't believe it.
The gods are good.
This guy's actually killable.
Insanity.
Thank God, man.
Squeezy.
Yes.
Good start.
Love that.
Moving on.
Now we can actually play the game.
I can't tell you how happy that makes me.
Actually, I can.
Mega happy.
I guess it is infinite range, you know?
So you can definitely use it for certain situations like this.
And I guess it does go through enemies.
So, you know, if enemies are stacked like that, it's really good.
I need a bomb here.
The finger is starting to grow on me.
I like having the finger on me.
Okay, destroy that.
Ah, man, I need a key.
What is this?
Yeah, that ain't happening.
I can do this.
That's kind of funny, isn't it?
Look at that range.
That's so funny.
I wonder if I can somehow buff the finger.
That'll be insane.
Like give it some kind of a damage multiplier, you know?
That'll be so cool.
I doubt it though.
Nice.
Thanks.
I really needed that key.
Ah, wait.
I thought maybe the finger could destroy the bomb.
Because it's like a special kind of damage, right?
See, now this icon makes me think this is gonna be bad for me.
Let's see if I'm right.
Oh, I got fire head.
Plus five bombs.
Bombs in place deal contact damage to enemies.
Isaac's bomb explosions leave behind fires that can damage enemies and block enemy shots.
Grants immunity to damage from stationary fires.
That's cool.
So it is actually good for me.
And we're on fire right now.
And more ways than one.
Okay, well, time for the boss.
This is one of the best starts we've had.
The question is, do I get in there now?
I need one here.
Actually, yeah, that's only two bombs, it seems.
And I should be immune to this, right?
Yeah.
Three chests.
Crackjacks, yes.
It doesn't get better than this, ladies and gentlemen.
If I don't make it this run, I will eat an ant.
That's right.
I will consume it.
I will chew on it.
I will swallow it.
I'm not gonna do that.
I hate ants.
But I'll think about doing it, which is almost just as bad.
Like, even right now, I'm shivering.
Good.
There we go, baby.
That's how you do it.
I'm not taking the deal.
Even though I have a million hearts, I'm gonna need them.
Trust me.
I will need every last milligram of soul heart there is.
If there's soul heart out there, I will mine it.
And I will process it, and I will refine it, and I will eat it.
Straight into the bloodstream.
Injection.
I cannot believe that.
I need keys.
Can I get any keys, or bombs, or bombs, or keys, or whatever it is?
What just happened?
Hold on.
Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on.
Maybe this opened because we did not access the treasure room yet.
And the shop.
Huh?
How about that?
Or it's depending on how fast you get to the room as soon as you enter the floor, you know?
Meaning, can you get to the room within four rooms or ten rooms?
If it's four rooms, it opens.
If it's not, it doesn't.
That's not true, because I've seen it as soon as I spawn, and it was closed, so that's not quite it.
Keys!
No.
My damage is somehow, all of a sudden, really bad.
Also, what's this?
Tears and shit.
That's good, that's good.
Come on.
Ah, man, come on.
All right, so far, so good here.
Definitely could have gone worse.
Nice.
That was nice and safe.
Oh, goodness gracious.
Good.
I feel like I'm locked in right now.
I have the motivation now that I got all these nice hearts.
This is what I needed.
It's a mental thing just as much as it isn't.
That was close.
Key acquired!
That means we're going to the treasure room.
Wait, that's the one that gives me randomized bomb effects.
Hmm.
Why not?
We're doing bomb things anyway, so why the hell not?
Oh, my fucking god.
Insanity!
I just lost four hearts.
I mean, two hearts.
Okay, I'm starting to develop a frown from the smile that I had earlier.
The frown is increasing.
That's not a good thing.
Okay, immediately consumed.
I'm gonna do this.
The hangman is good.
Very good.
Now to know where to use it.
I think we just go.
Hey, chop!
You like poop?
Here you go.
Suck on that.
Okay.
He's very angry.
This guy is actually kind of hard.
There you go.
You like that?
I bet you hated that.
What do we got?
Speed and shot speed?
Why not?
Moving on.
Actually, I have a lot of money, but I have no keys.
I gotta go back.
There's gotta be one key somewhere.
Oh, my fucking god.
That's a lot of enemies.
This is not looking great.
Well, if they stay over there, then I'm happy.
I'm gonna slowly move up here.
Oh, man.
That was totally not worth it.
No.
Not this room.
Okay, actually, I'm kind of... No.
Battery.
Well, no keys in sight.
Maybe there's a key I can get to while flying.
Somewhere?
Shit!
What a joke, dude.
I guess I'll be holding on to this money.
Next shop.
Next shop we're gonna buy.
It's not looking great.
We haven't really gotten any damage upgrades.
Massive angel chains increased just now.
Kill these at a safe range.
Now we get a key.
Not worth it to fly here.
Oh, now you're really tempting me.
I'll maybe come back.
We'll see.
Another key that's huge.
Oh, no.
Actually, I have developed a method.
Wait, how did I do this?
I go there?
Yeah, okay.
Fuck!
Just killed me already, man.
This room is so annoying.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
What is this?
Bot bombs?
I get all the bomb upgrades, huh?
Explosions damage and concuss all enemies.
I mean, I thought they already did damage enemies.
But I guess they do it more now?
Wait, did I just get another poop?
Am I just the poop man or what?
Wait, doorstop.
I didn't even realize I had that.
All right.
Oh, god.
Spider mod, but it's not gonna matter.
It doesn't even matter.
Hey, come here.
Once again, I'm asking for more soul hearts.
One soul heart.
Do I do it?
I think maybe... yeah.
Yeah, let's do it.
The husk?
What is that one?
Oh, those flies need to die first, though.
Oh, god.
Focus up, focus.
I got good range.
That's one thing I've got going.
No!
Not like this.
Well, it doesn't even matter, dude.
Like, I have no HP, so nothing matters.
It's just over.
Okay.
I'm sure we'll get lucky here and get some nice hearts.
The nail.
I don't know what that does.
It's not shooting nails.
Wow.
Okay, we can't walk in that crap.
You know what?
I'm flying.
I can't risk it.
It can't end like this.
Holy shit.
Spider butt.
Oh, god.
Oh, they were charmed.
Some of them were charmed.
Oh, man.
What?
What even happened?
I don't even understand what just happened.
I hate when I die to something that doesn't even make sense to me.
Like, I wasn't touching him.
Or maybe I was.
Didn't look like I was.
Ten coins?
Damn.
All right, all right, all right.
Starting off strong in the money department.
Not bad.
That was pretty bad, though.
I can't even get to the center and grab my reward.
This is just a fucking cruel joke.
How much do you want to bet if I play a Seizel now?
I'm gonna find flying within two minutes.
Like a permanent flying upgrade.
Even though I'm already flying.
I know it sounds ridiculous, but trust me.
That's just how it is.
Ten money, though, can't get you far.
Let's see.
Mom's bracelet is... grab and pick up a rock.
That is actually not bad.
I think that may be more handy than the heart.
No.
Heart all the way.
I don't even want to risk going into that fire.
These guys shoot things.
Like, only the ones with the eyes.
Oh, which makes sense, because they can't cry without eyes.
Well, if there's one thing I'm learning from all this, it's how to not take damage.
Even though I'm still, you know, taking damage.
I'm being forced to learn to dodge everything.
Imagine my power level when I finally go back to another character.
I can't even imagine the notion of healing up.
Healing?
That's crazy.
Nah, healing?
That's not a thing.
Oh god.
Okay then, sir.
You don't want to jump?
You don't want to jump.
That was clean as hell.
Beautiful.
Uh, we did not find the treasure room.
Right and down.
A key!
That's massive.
Really needed that.
Not bad at all.
Uh, oh no, is that the poopy butt?
kidney bean?
Absolutely horrible.
I feel like a fart would not charm enemies.
It was due the opposite.
It would send them running.
Especially this guy's farts.
He's been eating mom's lipstick.
Let's go this way.
I have a good feeling about rights.
Oh shit.
Oh hey, that was close.
Nearly botched it there.
Don't get close to that.
What was that sound just now?
There was like a key sound.
That was weird.
These guys also leave slight creep.
I just noticed.
Okay, not bad.
Uh, now where do I...
That's five coins.
That's definitely worth it.
And let's save the rest.
Spawn smaller ones.
Okay, that was clean.
Dude, I haven't seen a tinted rock in 10 years.
What is even happening?
Are they just not a thing when I'm playing this character?
Botfly, uh, deals contact damage and fire shield.
I guess that's that's one of the better ones, right?
I like this one.
It's not quite the one that goes in and absorbs the projectiles actively.
That one is incredible.
Oh nice, an absorbed one.
Good.
Is it worth destroying this?
Nah.
Eight coins.
Not worth it to spend the key on, not yet.
The donation machine is hilarious.
What's that?
Secondhand increases the duration of status.
Okay.
I'm not even gonna blow it up because I only have one bomb.
Oh, like this room is... what do you even do?
Like, what can you even do in this fucking room?
Like, it's just over.
I got fucked by RNG.
It's horrible.
That's pretty much the end of the run there.
I just don't have the DPS to carve my way through that.
Uh, yeah.
Oh, not these guys.
They leave bombs?
I feel like that's kind of new.
Or not.
But it thankfully damages them too.
Fuck.
I tried to push the bomb away.
A heart!
I need that.
That's why I stay on it.
Very good.
Okay, please be the good hearts.
Pill.
Of course.
Because I can't get the hearts I need.
Vibrant bulb?
Wait, that's new.
Speed and tears?
That's solid!
What a solid trinket.
A rare one.
You don't see that every day.
We got keys.
We can actually go to the shop now.
Now that I have it left over, why not?
I can even blow this up.
Ho ho!
Wow, that was totally worth it!
Please be good.
What is this?
Wait, what is the other one?
Plus three coins, spawns coins.
No.
We are going to take this.
Pay to play.
Money talks.
More coins.
Those and objects that normally...
Aww, that was not worth it.
I mean, maybe it is.
Actually, maybe it is worth it.
Let's not go too crazy too soon.
I think it may be alright.
Also, I haven't really farted in a while.
I should go fart.
Wait, whoa!
Hold on a minute.
Holy shit!
I missed the last part.
Grants an increase to all stats when held.
Active item is at full charge.
Wow!
That is a massive increase across the board.
Very good.
This may be one of the best trinkets.
I like it a lot.
Maybe worth.
Callus?
I am not sure what that does.
Alright guys, we need to die now.
No, stop picking it up!
Where are you going?
Okay.
Oh no.
Stop picking it up!
Fucking idiot.
What does it even do?
Wait, what does this even do?
Grants immunity to damage from...
Oh, actually, hold on now.
Well, well, well.
See, now I'm actually...
Dude, this is a great increase across the stat in stats.
But I need to keep my HP.
I need to keep these fees.
You gotta have the fees.
There are so many times you can just...
randomly step into some bullshit and you die, you know?
And I don't like that.
So I'm gonna reduce that as much as possible.
Charmed!
Okay.
Kinda wanna chase this guy into a corner and then do this.
Nice.
That was kinda good.
Why did he charge diagonally?
I was up left?
I don't understand the AI here.
It's like he knows what I'm going.
Well, we have one heart, so...
Man, I...
This is crazy.
This is...
The most insane experience in Ice Lake I've ever had.
Just fucking take me out of my misery.
If we don't get, like, 16 hearts within 5 minutes, we can't win.
Sure.
Nope.
Actually, yes.
Just kill me.
This room is just a joke.
Kill me.
I'm not even gonna bother with this.
No thanks.
That is an absolute hilarity right there.
Where are the good items, man?
Okay, you know what?
When I die now, I'm gonna play as Azul and you'll see.
I'm gonna get flying within 5 minutes.
You'll see.
There's something going on.
Like, I'm cursed.
I swear to you.
Okay, good.
And I haven't seen a single tinted rock as well.
Like, what are the chances of that even?
Not a single!
And secrets?
Where are they?
I am just so incredibly unlucky here, it's actually hard to explain.
Sir, will you please take damage?
Okay.
Not bad!
Hey!
100% the hit rate.
Oh wait, how am I even gonna deal with that?
That's how.
Beautiful.
Precision strikes.
Coin me.
Oh, okay.
Are there really no tinted rocks in here?
With this many rocks.
Crazy.
Nothing in here either.
I have a bomb, I'm ready!
Uh, may as well do that.
Just for the lulz.
Now I think I may go in there.
No, no, no, it's not worth it.
Yep.
Let's do it.
Let's see if I can stop getting hit by the first laser from this guy.
Oh wait, this is not that guy, is it?
It's a different one.
Yeah, this is not the laser dude.
Ah, come on then.
I have an idea.
As soon as he gets exhausted, I'm gonna bomb the shit out of him.
That is amazing.
What a strategy.
What an execution.
Nice!
More luck.
I feel like I haven't seen that many gambling machines either.
Like, what is hap- I feel like I'm in some sort of dystopian dream.
In Isaac.
Okay, so how do I even- I go around like this?
And now I'm surrounded.
Fuck!
Threading the needle.
Actually insane.
Okay, this way.
Oh god!
Okay, spiders first.
And then we focus on these guys.
Keys and bombs, solid.
Let's just have a peek.
Okay.
Okay, we got spiders.
Yeah, fuck me, man.
When they come from two sides, I don't even know how- how you're supposed to approach that.
Like, right here, what do I do?
You gotta move, like, insanely precise to even not take damage.
I mean, normally it wouldn't be a problem, right?
But to take a little bit of damage.
Because you can just heal it up when you find a heart.
Not on this character.
Little stuff like that, it starts to get really annoying.
All these little nuances where you just take random bullshit damage.
Because of, you know, random RNG of having enemies spawn there and there next to you, or whatever is going on.
You know, insert whatever.
Becomes, like, exponentially worse.
That's a new one.
Launches a ring of 10 large tiers each time I see- I don't want to take damage!
Chance to also briefly gain the anemic effect, whatever.
Useless items, no surprise.
The last thing I need to do on this character is take damage.
At least I'm getting a lot of flies.
Don't waste them on these.
I'm gonna arrange them.
Okay, well, he died.
Okay.
Come on.
I wait for you.
Good.
Why not?
It's the blight it's over.
That's for you.
This is the guy with the laser.
I dodged the first laser.
That has to be a good sign.
That has to mean this is the run, right?
Keep going.
This is how I feel in real life right now.
That dream was the perfect reflection of my current mental state.
Oh no, these are actually kind of scary.
They spawn big spiders that jump when they die.
Wait, what is happening?
Everything's moving faster.
Oh no, nevermind.
It was just because there was a tiny guy.
With a high pitched voice.
Am I crazy or is the game sped up right now?
A little bit.
I think it's just me.
I think I'm actually going crazy.
For some reason it looks like everything is just moving faster.
I'm losing my mind.
What was that direction change, bro?
That was like designed to fuck me in the ass and it did.
Oh, it did.
Gimme.
Ah man, I can go a lot of places.
So many choices.
Let's go left.
Place, I have one lock.
Be good to me.
Come on.
Of course.
Why am I surprised?
Or why am I surprised?
But I'm not though, so why am I not surprised?
I exist in a state of surprise.
And not surprised at the same time.
It means I don't feel anything.
I'm empty inside.
This room is fucking crazy, dude.
Can we talk about how crazy this fucking room is?
Like, I have no damage.
I got nothing.
This is harder than a boss.
It's over.
Like, what the hell is going on here?
I can't get to that.
Oh god, how am I gonna...
Kill this guy first.
Good.
And then we kill this guy.
Sniper.
Nice.
From downtown.
Oh no, not these.
Good thing I have save haven in the center here.
Not bad.
Good, good, good.
Tactical poop positioning.
TPP.
Okay, we got a good amount of money.
Oh well, six.
But it's still something.
We got half a heart.
Is there a way to just fucking restart?
Because... what's the point even?
Okay, let's go...
Oh, that's not gonna lead to the boss, right?
Actually, I...
Let me think.
Where could the boss be?
You know what?
He could be in here.
Who knows?
Okay, the shop is here.
Wait.
Get up.
Nice.
15... what is that?
BFF?
Okay, let's see.
I need to see what this does.
Or do I?
Do I need to see what it does?
I feel like I need to try a new item.
What is this?
Doubles the damage of familiars and increases their size.
That is unbelievably useless to me.
Kill me.
Right now.
Murder me on the spot.
Put that knife right in my bag.
I need it.
I need to just end it.
And I don't have the guts to do it myself.
I'm gonna have death by a wobbly guy here.
Wait, where did you guys come from?
Ah, who knows?
Maybe we'll find, like, five blue hearts in a second.
Hope.
It'll happen.
We'll find a super secret cache of super secret items.
And they're all gonna be blue.
Da-ba-di-da-da.
You there.
Would you like to join me for an extended session of...
Oh!
I can't believe I haven't found the boss yet.
Like, I've been everywhere.
Maybe over here.
What if he's right here?
He ain't.
A mushroom.
I have no damage.
It's pathetic.
Like, I'm tickling them.
I guess he must be in the south.
Oh, no.
Okay, good.
Start over.
Oh, no, we're lost!
I don't like that.
Okay, you know what, actually?
No, thanks.
Take me the fuck out.
Horrible.
Holy shit!
That's a lot of enemies.
Oh, wait, I forgot I wanted to play Azazel.
Okay, when I die again, I'm gonna do Azazel.
And you'll see the luck coming immediately, like, on point.
Okay, now please give me something good.
Come on.
What's that?
Chart of glass.
Chance to spawn a red heart when damaged.
Taking damage will make Isaac gush blood tears.
Every 20 seconds while bleeding, lose half a red heart.
Uh, okay.
Running out of red hearts or healing red hearts will stop.
Fucking useless to me.
The game was designed around red hearts and this guy is stupid.
Like, that's a shitty character, man.
Absolutely horrible.
Let's go up here.
And just go window shopping, because there's no way in hell I'll ever be able to afford this.
Actually, these items are not even good.
I don't even want them.
You can have them.
That's fine.
It's Steven Seagal.
Oh no, we're under siege!
Lowkey, a, like, average movie.
I wouldn't even call it a bad movie.
It's average.
You know?
Under siege.
I know Steven Seagal is like a massive fucking joke, and he is.
But that movie is like...
It'll pass, you know?
It's barely good enough to be, you know, average.
Dude, what do you want from me?
Come on.
I saw this YouTube video with Steven Seagal where...
He's really into the, like, the Japanese sort of karate chops and, you know, all these things.
And he's standing there in his kimono or whatever the fuck it's called, you know, in the dojo.
And he looks so stupid.
It's so funny.
And he's like...
He's so slow and clumsy when he does his moves.
And he speaks as if he has this lifelong wisdom.
It is just the worst.
I can't watch it.
It is so bad.
You should check it out, man.
It is something else.
And some of those movies it's been in, like, some of the later ones.
I've got the names of them, but it is just a disaster in every way.
He's this overweight, really fat, slow, unlikeable character in the movie.
That is supposedly this special ranger, you know, who has the skills that the government calls upon when they need the best of the best.
And then he talks in this sort of voice all the time to be super important sounding and cool sounding.
And it's just not, you know, it's like he's in his own world.
It's crazy.
Brain worm, missed shots turn 90 degrees, huh?
We got to experiment with that a bit.
I had it once before, but I don't recall exactly how it works, but...
Hey, OK.
Hey, that's actually kind of cool.
I'm digging that.
I'm caught in a corner.
Yo, the brain worm.
The first good item we found.
That is something else here.
Actually, we found one other good item, which was...
What was it?
The eyedrops or whatever, the ones that made our shots do a lot of damage nearby.
You know, that was a good item.
But ever since, you know, not quite.
Don't shoot me.
Good.
All right.
No treasure room.
That is such a shame.
I need one.
Can't go on without it.
What the fuck, man?
Almost every room I enter, I go, Man, I wish I was a Zazel.
Man, I wish I was a Zazel.
I wish I had set 21.
That's the guy with the smokes in the magic show.
He puts all the smokes in his mouth.
OK, take me out of my misery.
We're going to a Zazel now, because I am about done with this shitty character.
Holy shit, that can suck my ass.
You ready?
You ready for the ultimate fucking Luxpree?
Number one, extra tiers, less range.
A lot of less range.
I don't think that's good for me.
Actually, let's try it.
I mean, honestly, the range feels about the same.
Am I crazy?
That range is pretty much identical.
Or like very tiny amounts there, you know?
OK, I'm going to do drive-by.
Oh, we even have bombs.
Look at that tinted rock off the fucking bat!
Two hearts!
Five coins!
Emergency contact!
Uh-oh.
Fucking machine I haven't seen in 10 years is appearing!
What's that?
Dim bulb!
I think it's broken?
Oh, that's interesting.
Grant's an increase to all stats when held...
Oh, that's the opposite of the IC!
That's smart.
I like it.
So wait, does it have an effect now?
I guess I don't have an active.
We got this one as well!
I'm moving on.
No, we're going to blow it up.
We're going to get an eternal heart.
OK, but five bombs, I'll take it.
Or four, or however many that was.
All right, let's go.
Let's go smack the boss.
Oh, that was bad.
Jumping now.
OK, this boss is actually kind of tough.
It's a tough boss.
She's going to jump again.
Good.
Wait, oh, this guy's still alive.
Dark food.
You love the dark food.
I love the dark food.
It's so good.
Moving on.
Oh, yeah, give me that music.
Curse of the Lost doesn't even matter.
Like, look at this.
He wants he wants bombs.
I got bombs.
That's exactly what I got.
It's like meant to be.
There you go.
What am I going to get in return?
Nice.
How about an item?
OK, I'll take that too.
Right before the shop.
He's giving me items every time I give him items.
Holy shit, right before.
I love it.
Thank you, man.
So nice of you.
Oh, would you look at that?
A blue heart.
When I don't need it.
Oh, that's all my.
Maybe I shouldn't have used all my bombs, actually.
I may have fucked up a little bit there.
I got carried away.
That's on me.
It's OK.
I think it's kind of cool that we have the burning basement.
We're going to need a key.
Look for a key.
Oh, should I go in there?
Wait, wait, wait.
Twelve coins.
Yeah, let's go in here.
Monster manual.
What's that?
Telepathy for dummies.
Gain homing tears and increase range for the current room.
But wait, that doesn't affect me.
I don't think my laser beam is going to be bending anywhere.
I like this one.
We're going to take both, though.
And then take this one back.
Oh, wait a minute.
Plus damage.
Plus lock as well.
Hold on a minute now.
Oh, it's because I see now, because we have the vibrant bulb.
Makes sense.
Yeah, let's use this.
But why is it zero now and not?
Maybe didn't have time to refresh.
That's probably what it is.
Thank you for the keys.
Let's see what I get in here.
That's amazing.
Tears up.
We love to see it.
That one is also amazing.
Thank you.
Oh, we got people.
There you are.
I hate when we got people.
Little horn chance to fire what tears to summon Bighorn's hand to attack.
That's a good one.
Bighorn's hand instantly kills normal monsters.
Yeah, this is a good one.
This one is the dark bomb.
Familiar that consumes red heart pickups and drops black hearts.
Hills cards.
Blue spider.
No.
Give me that one.
Yeah, I'm happy with that.
And we have the emergency contact.
And a pill.
Speed down.
Doesn't matter.
I was too fast anyway.
Amazing.
We even got one of these again.
A soul heart.
You love to see it.
Size down.
I've never even seen size down on the other character.
This is insanity.
Give me that.
I need the bombs though.
Just a couple.
Oh yeah, I can't take damage.
Also, I really should be using this.
Because it lasts for the floor, right?
I can't see the map, but that's...
You know what?
Let's go back to the shop.
Because I have a key now.
Was it this way?
I think it was.
There it is.
Mom's razor.
Orbital familiar that blocks enemy shots.
Deals contact damage.
Okay, okay, okay.
Waiting enemies take damage over time.
That's good.
I like it.
I like that it's pink as well.
It's fitting.
Let's do it.
The gurglings.
Like on a girdle on my lane.
That didn't even make sense.
I'm sorry.
That was terrible.
Wait, oh, I'm really not paying attention here.
A bar of soap?
I think shot speed is useless to me.
Right, that was that.
We keep moving on.
Okay.
Ah, that was bad.
I'm too greedy.
As soon as I'm playing on this carry, I'm like, ah, let's just fucking go, you know?
Do I want this?
I don't want this.
Then again.
Nah, they're not that good.
What's that?
Oh my, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
This one's good.
I like this one.
Oh yeah, definitely.
We're taking this and watch it.
Yeah!
Sick!
And then I...
No, no, no, I keep this actually.
I keep this for sure.
I'm even going to buy this.
That's really great.
I'm lacking a little bit of damage here.
Well, that's okay.
I'm sure I'll get blessed with a damage item in just a minute here.
But in the next three minutes, for sure.
It is just reliable luck you get when you play Azazel, you know?
It's not even luck.
It's just how it is.
It's part of the daily routine.
Now we go for the corridor.
Wait, what's happening?
I don't even know what's happening.
That was confusing.
Whoa.
Go in here.
Good.
Ah, the question is, do I go in yet?
You know what, why not?
Why not?
Oh, it's Gertie.
Haven't seen you in 10 years, man.
Actually, that's not true.
I saw him when everything was sped up on the other character, on question mark.
Oh, shit.
Nice.
The hand of Satan.
We love the snack.
We love the blue heart.
Let's go look for the treasure room.
Right here.
I think my rule now is going to be, we do that until we're at two bombs.
And then we can stop.
Oh, God.
Okay, what about right here?
And here?
I could go in there.
I may do it.
Yeah, let's do it.
What's that?
Oh, it's my friend following me.
The little guy with the blue hair.
I was like, what the hell is happening?
Gimme.
I was orbiting that coin.
Milk, this is a familiar.
That one is a good one.
Damage protection is massive.
Come out, come out.
Okay, surely here.
Guess we're done here.
Did I check this?
Ah, good.
Helps when you have a lot of bombs, you know.
Oh, God.
Ah, really?
Playing bad.
I'm too eager.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Let me have that.
Dude, I can't wait to use me seeks on a devil deal.
It's gonna be glorious.
Oh, nice.
Oh, that's both of my keys.
Maybe we wait a bit.
Play safe.
Who knows?
Maybe we find something else we want to spend the key on.
Never mind.
That's not just a bomb out of nowhere.
That's unusual.
Let me also double check this item again.
This one.
Ghosts can attack enemies, fetch items, press buttons.
Open most doors.
Ah, and sometimes steal shop, I see.
Okay, open most doors.
Most doors, you say.
So I probably couldn't open that door just now, is my guess.
But who knows?
Yeah, that one was a bit risky.
Oh, God.
I don't know how much HP I have.
It's scary.
We have a battery there.
Oh, that was a lot of coin.
Thanks.
Nice.
That's huge.
Tractor beam!
So how does that work with this one?
Maybe it doesn't.
I guess it's useless on this guy.
Let me see.
It is a bunch of good upgrades, though, like stats-wise.
Yeah.
Not amazing.
But better than nothing.
Let's dodge master!
Did you see that?
Slalom.
Please be health up.
Oh!
Right, right, right, right, right, right, right, right, right.
That's that.
This one's unidentified.
There we go.
He wants coins!
Good for him, I got coins.
Give me some...
What if I use the Mr. Me on this guy?
Can I put him in my backpack?
Take him with me.
Dessert!
Yay!
Huge!
That is so massive for me.
Very good.
And then we go in here.
And maybe regret that we have 14 coins now.
Let's see.
Ah, eraser?
I don't want that, actually.
But I'm
gonna erase one guy and come back and grab the other.
It'll be good.
Trust.
Who do I hate?
I hate these guys.
What?
Did I miss?
It looked like I hit him.
I don't know what just happened there.
I feel like that was a...
That was a hit.
What is happening?
This is like fucking...
Whoa!
The front lines here.
Jesus Christ.
Warzone.
Wish you could see my HP here.
I really don't know how much I have.
Want to make sure...
Oh, that's not good, though.
That's not the worst, either.
So did I find everything I want to find?
It looks like it.
Yeah.
Here we go.
I think I'm gonna call in emergency contact here just to use it.
Not bad.
Nice.
What do we get?
Tropicamide.
Tear size increase.
So here's the thing.
I don't know how much HP I have.
So this is a little...
Oh, the pact.
Two red hearts is interesting.
I think I'm gonna do it.
I don't know how much HP I have right now.
I'm totally gambling, man.
Please, I need to see my HP now.
What do I have?
Probably four black hearts or something.
Yeah, exactly four black hearts.
Not too bad, actually.
Oh god, oh god.
Oh god, I got hit by the freaking guy in the center.
That's embarrassing.
Oh shit, I forgot to...
I forgot about Mr. Meeseeks!
Well, that's a massive blunder right there.
That is actually insanely bad.
Okay, here's the plan.
Yeah!
Suck on that.
Nice.
Still happy about it.
Flat file!
Uh, that's useless for me.
You know what?
Why not?
Let's go in here.
The cage!
I haven't seen this guy in a lot of time.
It's been a minute.
What if I erase you?
It's not gonna work on bosses, right?
I also threw it in the wrong direction.
Nice.
The screw.
Shot speed.
I think that's also useless for me, actually.
Maybe it does have an effect on the laser, but I don't know what it is.
It could be also contributing to my charge speed.
How fast I charge up the laser.
Maybe.
I don't think so.
Never really know.
Oh no.
Yeah!
Thanks.
What is it?
Beautiful!
That's the exact kind of luck I expect.
And the serve.
That's a good one as well.
The Empress is solid.
More range.
Don't mind if I do.
My range is getting respectable.
Look at that.
That's pretty good.
Whoa!
What's this demon character?
Come on.
Show me the good stuff.
Okay.
I got exactly 15.
Every fourth room is slowed by 50%.
Oh, 13% chance to speed enemies up.
Oh, okay.
I mean, I think that's pretty good.
Odds are in my favor.
By quite a bit.
I'm gonna hang out in the center, where I feel safe.
Is this my safe space right here?
Sir!
Thank you.
This room would have been fucking...
horrible.
Ass question mark.
I almost ran into the fire!
Did you see that?
Caught myself in time.
Let's go in here.
Re-chests!
Yo!
Two blue hearts?
Don't mind if I do.
Oh, god.
Uh-oh.
What's happening?
Is someone behind me?
Oh, yeah, okay.
Oh, my god.
Four blue hearts in here?
Shoot.
Not bad.
Plus two damage.
That is also pretty good.
This one's better, though.
I didn't mean to do that.
I totally just ran into it.
Ayy!
Amazing.
Our range is gonna be nuts.
We're turning into a brimstone.
Manual brimstone.
Now, do I go in there?
I think so.
It slowed down.
Okay, well, not super worth it.
What?
Oh.
I'm scared of the time that this room is gonna be sped up, you know?
That's gonna be a surprise when it happens.
I wonder if those rooms, or the boss rooms, count in that sort of, you know, every four room?
Whoa, almost ran into the fire again.
Oh, wait, this one I've seen before.
This is the teleport.
No.
Launches a targeted airstrike.
That's actually pretty good.
I like this.
Let's leave.
What?
Third time I almost did it.
Okay.
Solid so far.
Now it's mom time.
We're gonna slap her.
Right across the face.
Right hand.
Boom!
Oh, that was a bit too easy.
Why am I going in so fast?
I should just calm down a bit.
Oh, god.
Wow.
Kind of want to step a little bit.
But not with black hearts.
That's kind of a bad idea.
I like that the music is also slowed down.
What a great touch.
Perfect.
Contact again.
Actually, hold on.
The contact is really good against the bosses.
Hold them in place and just...
Dude, hold them in place and then use the airstrike.
What a combo.
Huh?
Tell me that isn't amazing.
Oh, it sped up, sped up.
Honestly didn't mind it.
That key is so clutch right now.
That was risky, so I shouldn't have done that.
Uh, wait, why did I go in here?
I don't have any money.
That was bad, actually.
I should have used it on the chest instead.
Ah.
Another key.
We can get the chest.
Uh, squeezy?
Oh my god.
There they are.
Like, I would love to get something like that, you know?
When I'm playing question mark.
Just give me all the blue hearts.
Because that's the only thing I really want.
Wait, we missed a room.
Treasure room has not been found.
Alert, alert.
Go to my save space.
Wow, he jumped to me.
Save space is no longer safe.
Another key.
That is so important.
Ludo Vico!
I-I'm telling you.
You get- Ah, I ran into it finally!
The fucking tears were blocking my vision.
I swear to god, I'm not just blaming it on that, but it's true.
Isaac!
The yellow circle of death shall punish you!
Watch this.
We're gonna do that.
We're gonna do this.
Boom, baby!
Your days are numbered!
What's that?
Missing page two.
Black heart, room-wide damage upon taking a hit there with- Nah.
It's not that exciting.
Guarantees- Ooh, now that!
Abba, wait.
We only have one more floor we can make use of it.
So it's actually not that good.
This one is one red heart.
Wait, I actually have pretty low damage.
I just noticed.
I need damage.
So I'm gonna- I'm actually gonna take that.
Maybe there's a chance we get damage later in another deal.
I need the damage.
Okay.
There we go.
I gotta get used to playing with this ring again.
Oh, wait, whoa, whoa, whoa, hold on.
Why is my ring moving on its own?
Look, I'm not touching it.
I move it to the right and then it sort of just comes back automatically.
Huh?
That's weird!
It's following me, look!
I wonder why that is.
I thought it would stay in one spot.
Oh, I'm gonna be blocking my own view here.
Gotta be careful.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, go, go, go, go, go, go, go!
Beautiful.
This is one big circle of yellow.
It's Pizfasa.
Oh, that was not good.
I shouldn't have taken damage there.
I need to find another emergency contact.
In case I get lost.
I need a lifeline here.
You know, my HP situation is actually not that great.
That is the one thing you can say right now.
It was quite terrible, actually.
Definitely going in here.
Love it.
Nice, very nice.
I go south.
Whoa!
Amazing.
I don't know why this circle is following me.
That is so weird.
That has never happened when I've had this.
Okay.
See ya, buddy.
Wonderful.
Actually, that doesn't matter anymore, because my tears are constant.
Like, I have a constant cry going on right now.
Should I be opening that?
Nah.
I think I should take one heart of damage when I do things here now.
I gotta play extra safe.
What the hell is that?
He has a skull on him!
Huh?
What is that?
That's new!
Never seen that.
I wonder what I just did.
Hopefully, it's good.
This...
Oh, the sun.
The sun!
Coins?
I don't have any, man.
I got no coins for ya.
Uh-oh.
There's the boss.
And that is, uh, not the mom.
That is the in-betweener.
Lovely.
Okay.
I guess we're doing mom.
Wait, uh, before I do.
No, it's not mom.
What am I saying?
It's not mom.
It's the in-betweener.
Anything good for me?
Last coin?
No.
Here.
That's your punishment.
I have a hundred percent...
Oh yeah, devil is because I got the item.
Makes sense.
The fallen.
He kind of looks like a mini Satan.
Ah, I shouldn't have get hit there.
That was bad.
False PhD!
Converge most gold.
I need to remember what this does.
Oh, this is the bad pill one, but it's still kind of good.
Uh, right.
I mean, that's amazing.
We love that.
We take that.
Oh, my goodness!
What's happening here?
Oh, you're so slow.
That's just too bad, ain't it?
So, less tears.
More damage.
That is good for me with the Ludo Vico.
We take that.
Lomp of cold makes tears increase in damage and size that...
Father, does that even...
I wonder if this is actually better.
Having the ring be bigger.
I guess it is, right?
For AoE purposes.
But there's also a big area in the center now.
Wait, it's sort of pulsing in radius.
Less speed.
I actually don't mind.
We can go less speed, more damage.
Any kind of damage right now is going to be huge for me.
Moving on.
Coins, eh?
Eh, mate?
Not right now.
Turn off, turn off.
Good.
This room is actually crazy.
If you're not as Hazel.
Feels bad being slowed down, doesn't it?
Uh, should we go in here?
Nah.
I value my hearts pretty highly right now.
Because I don't have a lot.
Oh, yeah, the big ring is actually goaded.
Big ring is good.
Oh, whoa, whoa, what am I doing?
Did I just walk into a rock like an idiot?
I think I did.
Well, that was bad.
I was looking at my ring, not on my character.
Did we get an item?
Rosary bead increases the chance of encountering the Bible?
When a devil room would appear, an angel room appears...
Ooh, wait.
So that means I can guarantee an angel room.
Let's do that!
Fuck yeah, man.
That's funny.
That means I'm gonna get 100% angel now, look.
To be honest though, like, the items I've seen in the angel room kind of suck.
I've had quite a bit of angel rooms today, and they've all been super bad.
Wait, where's this sword I have following me?
There's a sword.
Which one is that?
You see that?
I'm not sure what that is.
Did I maybe get three out of three on something?
Leviathan, one out of three.
Yes, mother.
No.
Okay, I'm not sure.
Dear lord.
Three buttons.
Three chests, maybe?
What's that?
Ah, wait, wait, wait.
Let's remember this is here.
That's interesting that that just appears like that.
I just noticed the eye has to turn before it can shoot, and it's turning quite slowly.
There's the boss.
Wait a minute, I'm gonna do something really strategic here.
The question is though, does this work on empty rooms?
My slowdown thingy.
See, every fourth room is slow, so 50%.
This is one, two, three, four.
Wait a minute.
One, two, three.
Maybe it's only on uncleared rooms that count, so this should be counting as one now.
This is one, so nothing happens.
Two, and then we keep the counter, so it's two still.
Let's keep going back.
Now we take it to three.
Uh, wait a minute.
This is three now.
Uh-oh, what's this?
Oi, okay.
Man, that was amazing.
I heard something drop in here.
Okay, so we're at three now.
Now I'm gonna go back to the boss room.
The boss room should be slowed now or sped up if we're unlucky.
Let's see if I'm right.
Yeah, it lifts.
Wait, what?
What's happening?
Uh, hold on a second.
I'm gonna go over here and do this.
Yeah, what the fuck?
This is all new.
Oh, wait, wait, wait.
We can get beamed up.
Hold on.
What's that?
The wafer.
Thank you.
That's a great item.
It's of course a great item because I'm on a sasil now.
So you get the best items.
It's just how that works.
This is so cool.
Wow.
Cathedral, baby.
And we got the Ludo Vico technique.
Surely the...
See, the ring was a little too big there.
I almost couldn't, you know, hit enemies with it because it's too damn large.
If there's a narrow room, I don't even know if I can hit anything.
Okay, so this...
So now we're counting again.
Oh, shit.
Two.
Lost losing a lot of HP here, though.
This is not good.
Let me have a look around here.
Give me that.
I got 21 bombs.
Let me just blow some of these up.
Maybe there's like a secret.
Look at that.
There's like a cross on the floor.
On a necklace.
You can probably dig there.
Oh, I would love to dig there.
I forgot the count.
I think we're at three now.
Double Isaac's red hearts.
I mean...
Wait, where's my son?
I must have...
I think I forgot it somewhere.
Yeah, now it's four again.
Oh, wait.
This is the guy controlling him.
Or shielding him, I should say.
Now the count is one.
Oh, crap.
Oh, man.
That did a lot.
Or a boros.
Oh, wait a minute.
Hold on.
Tears firing up.
Okay, that's not affecting me or...
Chance for homing tears that increases with luck.
Nah, I like my rosary beat.
Faith up.
We're in the cathedral.
We gotta have faith, right?
All right, let's just start bombing things.
Shape that's across this hole.
Let me bomb it.
Ah, okay.
What about there?
No?
Okay.
I'm not doing great with HP here.
This is looking really rough.
Oh, shit.
I'm gonna stay in a corner.
Stay in a corner and kill everything with the fucking circle.
I can move it off screen.
Look.
I don't even know what I'm hitting.
This room is crazy looking.
Dude, I love this place.
This is so good.
Wow.
Wait a minute.
I have an idea.
Are you thinking what I'm thinking, partner?
I gotta find something that is clearly a floor decoration, though.
Like, all of this looks so...
weirdly decorated.
I don't know which one should count, but maybe...
You know, maybe that broke a hole in the floor.
I don't think that's so outlandish.
I'm gonna save my charges, though, for the boss.
I'm gonna get two more charges here.
Or one charge, I mean.
I don't want that.
Two of hearts.
No, this one's better.
We're gonna use this later.
Okay, we gotta be careful now.
What is this treacherous room?
And I summon blue hearts.
Yeah!
I just know when it'll happen.
What can I say?
Okay, we need to get charged, so...
Gotta find a room where we can kill some enemies.
Would love to gamble, as well.
But is that kind of forbidden in the church?
Gambling at church.
Maybe that's a sin or something.
I don't know.
Probably, right?
Okay, so wait, this is...
Okay, we're at zero.
We're at zero.
We're gonna wait, we're gonna wait.
Okay.
Get out of there.
Okay, we're still at one.
Two.
Let's take this one.
I don't know if this counts.
There's no enemies.
It's got a count, right?
That's a lot of money.
Let's go back.
Oh wait, I don't think it counts.
That needs to be enemies.
Uh, fuck, do I gamble and go in here?
For science.
No, it did count!
Oh, okay, so we're at zero now.
Damn.
Fine.
Okay, this is still zero.
One.
The circle is too big!
Oh god!
Okay, we're at one.
But there's no more rooms!
Shit!
I need one more room.
There's actually one room.
There's one room we can do.
But I gotta go in here first.
Where are they?
Okay.
We're at two right now.
Beautiful.
Now we're gonna get three up here by the, um, the stepity step.
And then we don't do anything in there, we just go back.
Because we know it counts now.
You ready?
Oh, we're gonna take, uh, one blue heart damage here, though.
Wait, should I be doing this?
Yeah.
Oh!
Insane.
Yes!
That is so needed right now.
Insanity.
And that's three.
Here we go, baby!
You ready for number four?
It's coming up!
Wait, wait, what was that one?
No, I need the two hearts here, I think.
We could get unlucky now and have it sped up, imagine.
Come on, please, please slow down.
Yes!
You're slow, dude!
You're slow!
Boom!
You like that?
Look how slow you are, though.
Oh, he went off into the heavens.
Oh, god, oh, god, oh, god!
Okay, put that on his face.
That's okay, we're totally chilling.
Look at me, man.
This is genius.
Good night, sir!
Good night!
Except, wait, do we continue?
Can we continue?
Somehow.
I'm not sure.
I don't think so, there's no way to go down.
Here it is!
We got a bright idea.
What is it?
We both realized something was wrong with the chest, I guess.
I'm not sure what just happened.
Why do we both look at the chest like that?
Well, listen to the music.
It's changed.
Wait, what are they saying?
He loves you and he loves me.
Oh, Jesus loves you.
Can't you see?
Oh my god, that's so messed up.
What the...
This feels like a special ending we got here.
This is disturbing.
I don't want to interrupt it, I want to hear the whole song.
I wonder if that credits actually change between these endings.
Someone named Ass on the team?
He just named Ass.
Haha, the Satanic Bible has appeared.
All right, I need to see something now.
Wait!
Okay, so we have fully filled out two parts of...
It almost looks like a picture or something.
There's a little child, a flower on the right, and maybe...
No, maybe that's a mom or a dad or something.
Family photo, perhaps.
I don't know.
Who's our dad?
Think about that for a second.
Think about your dad.
Guys, I'm telling you.
As soon as you jump on a sasle, you get insane luck.
Where was all this luck when I was playing the other character?
Like I had like 10 runs in a straight row, maybe more.
Nothing.
And all of a sudden, boom.
Right?
I don't know what's happening, but that's the end of that.
That was both an amazing and really painful session in many ways.
What's going on, guys?
What say you to that?
Wow!
Meeps kitten!
What's up, dude?
50 community subs!
Thank you very much!
Holy shit, that's 50!
Wow!
Damn!
At 186 now total, that is crazy, man.
Thank you so much.
Happy to see you enjoying.
I'm so grateful, man.
Thank you.
I'm glad you're enjoying it so much that you want to donate those subs to people.
That's awesome.
For those that don't know, I'm sorry, maybe I'm cringy for saying this every time, but I'm just like, you know, this guy's a fucking...
He went to space, okay?
Meeps kitten went to space.
And he just bought me some subs.
I've made it, you know?
Like, that's crazy.
No, no, actual space.
He went up in a rocket with... I forget the name now, but...
What was it?
Remind us, Meeps.
What was the rocket called?
Or the shuttle or whatever it was?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Oh, there's an ending?
Yeah, I'm going to check it next time.
I realized I was going to get an ending because I skipped the heart, right?
Or in this case, it lives.
It was cold.
I have 2,000 hours in this game, and watching you stumble your way through this game is like, cracked to me.
Are you sure about that, Karmic?
Are you sure you don't have recency bias for the last run?
And not, you know, all the question mark runs we had earlier today?
It was the new Shepard stuff with Blue Origin.
That's right, Blue Origin, right.
It was an honor to be involved, but I'm just a kid.
I mean, dude, whatever you are, if you're in space, you're kind of awesome.
No matter the argument in your life from now on, you know, if you're losing an argument with your, I don't know, significant other or a friend and you know you're in a corner, you can't win, you just go, I've been to space!
And that shuts them down, you know?
I hope you pull out that card.
I'm kidding.
Of course, it's not like an argument for anything, but I just thought it was funny.
I think I heard that somewhere.
I forgot where.
It's like the funniest thing.
When I heard that, it made me laugh so much.
The person with the highest Eden win streak in Isaac currently has one more than 4,200 more.
Okay, but that's Eden.
Let's see, let's see, uh, fuck.
Now I can't, I messed up the reference.
Let's see, uh, Paul's card or let's see, you know, the guy.
Oh my God, what's the character?
The question mark.
The fucking insert meme, that makes sense.
You'll know what I mean.
Paul Allen, that's it, thank you.
Thank you.
Hospital would kill me?
I do have a literal card though.
That's awesome.
What'd you do?
That's freaking awesome.
Wait, you just have a card you give to people that said, in parentheses, small font, I've been to space.
I'm kidding, that's obviously not what it says, but maybe you have like a business card or something.
I went to space on a rocket and all I got was this card.
And some great views, I hope.
Wait, what is this?
People are spamming, uh, weird stuff.
Alien dance day, quad really cool mess.
I don't know what that means, guys.
It's like this metal thing.
Oh, that's fancy.
A fancy metal card.
That's crazy.
Oh wait, I'm not seeing the alien dance, guys.
It's because I'm looking at, uh, oh my god.
I don't know why it's like turning off.
I think it's either 7 TV or the Frankie TV or whatever it was called.
It's not working for me.
Like it keeps turning off and I don't know why.
But I can see it on the OBS preview.
Yeah, I see it here.
I told you we went to war.
And boy was it a battlefield today.
Bombs flying left and right.
Dying on purpose left and right.
Like what was even happening today?
I love the alien dance.
It's kind of aligned with the music right now.
Isn't it?
Like look at his feet.
He's dancing to the beat.
Maybe it's just on my end here.
Maybe it's too late for you guys.
But it's perfect here.
We're starting this while I've been, uh, binging Mugenics on my own.
It's been great.
Yeah, everyone's talking about Mugenics.
It's like his new game, the guy who made this game.
And it's supposedly really good.
I feel like it's like the perfect game for you, right?
It was like made for you.
Great timing to play this.
Yeah, actually.
I had no idea about Mugenics until people told me.
When I started this.
Hold R to restart in Isaac.
Oh, really?
I didn't know that.
That's that's a good tip.
Oh, I should start doing that instead.
This is just dying on...
I feel like it's more dramatic though to die on purpose.
I learned restart now.
We're gonna be...
I'm gonna be pressing R so much, guys.
If the first room I don't find Brimstone, I restart.
I'm kidding.
I was definitely on a bit of a on a streak today.
Okay, let's just say that.
I was deep in the rabbit hole and I couldn't dig myself out of it and I let it happen.
Sometimes you're in that mental state and you need to embrace it.
Instead of trying to slowly crawl out of the hole, just fall down all the way, you know?
Let go of the handrails.
Go into free fall and hit the ground with a massive bang.
Sometimes that's what it takes.
Or you switch over to Azazel and immediately win the entire game.
It was incredible to witness.
I don't know about that.
I mean, I may have sounded a little tilted, but I was actually having a blast with it.
Like, I thought it was kind of funny.
I was imagining you guys probably going crazy about that.
And that was entertaining to me.
But I was a little tilted.
But right?
Like, tell me I didn't learn a lot from the question mark.
I feel like I learned to dodge way better.
Like, I developed some skills there for sure, right?
Something I can apply with every character.
It wasn't time wasted.
That's for sure.
Good practice, exactly.
You got 120 streaks.
What the...
Guys, when do you think I'm going to be able to get to a 10 win streak?
With like mixed characters.
Maybe not including question mark.
They're going to become muscle memory when you sleep.
Five months.
Maybe five soon.
Wait, what does five soon mean?
The next 10 runs.
Frank!
You know how to please me.
That's exactly what I needed to hear.
You're right.
The next 10 runs have been a sasle.
Thank you, Frank.
A sasle it is.
You called it into...
You made it happen, you know?
Like, you summoned it.
You made it...
You manifested it.
Oh,
I actually wanted to do challenges today.
And the greed mode.
But I got so absorbed by the question mark guy.
The blue...
The blue boy.
Let's just call him blue boy.
That it was getting personal.
I was like, you know what?
There's no way.
I can't let this stand.
And then I actually ended up giving up on that.
Question mark, what's the challenge?
You know what?
You're so right.
Yeah.
True.
You're gonna turn into a sasle?
I am already slowly becoming a sasle in real life.
I have developed horns.
I'm slightly lifting off the ground.
I haven't developed a laser from my mouth yet or my eyes, but maybe it'll happen.
By the way, isn't the laser out of eyes guy pretty much the guy from...
What's that series called?
The boys.
That's him.
The boys, dude.
You didn't take any devil deals so it's understandable.
Early floors being hard.
Yeah, but the thing is, it's a balance, right?
You can take devil deals and lose HP.
Gain better upgrades.
Or you don't and you actually have HP to survive with.
It's a fine balance.
You gotta run there.
It's a blood laser.
That can't be healthy.
Yeah, you should die of blood laws, I guess.
Blood puke.
That doesn't sound good at all.
I don't know what metal slug is, businessman.
Why not play on normal?
Do I look like a guy who plays on normal?
Come on.
Speaking of difficulties, the funny thing is people were like in the comments of the Terraria stuff.
Man, you shouldn't have picked expert.
It was the worst decision ever.
I don't know why you did that, you know?
And then in the comments of...
What's it called?
Expedition 33, everyone's like, why didn't you pick expert?
Why did you go with normal?
You should totally have picked expert.
Like, dude, I don't know what the game is going to be like.
I'm not even kidding.
That's what the comments are right now.
It's so funny.
That's why I like games like Dark Souls that have no difficulty, you know?
I mean, there's just one difficulty that everyone has.
I like that.
Yeah, it's kind of weird to me that this game has normal and hard.
Why not just have one, you know?
Give a name for question mark.
I told you, it's Blue Boy.
His name is Blue Boy.
The BB.
Yeah, Blue Boy.
Blueberry.
The blueberry.
I like a big boss.
That's also a good one.
Or a bad bitch.
Although right now he's not a bad bitch.
He's a very pathetic bitch.
He's a PB.
Right?
It should just have one difficulty.
I feel like that's way more appropriate.
I forgot whether or not Hades had multiple difficulties.
I know that was a way to make the runs harder.
I'm talking about Hades 1 here.
Where you put, like, extra difficulties on, but you also had more rewards, potentially.
But, like, for games like this, you know, one difficulty, I think makes more sense.
How far in the game do you think you are now?
Well, I looked at the endings today, and I think I'm over halfway.
Based on that.
And you can go clueless if you want.
Because I don't even believe half the times you guys write that.
Because half of you are joking, half of you are not, and it's just become a mishmash.
Yeah, see, people are writing 0.2 percent, right?
Yeah, right.
You can write clueless, that's fine.
Go for it.
I don't believe it.
Maybe I believe it 50 percent.
Maybe like 57 percent.
All right, guys.
This was a long stream, actually.
Holy shit.
It has been over five hours.
Five hours and 20 minutes, damn.
I really got absorbed in blue boy today.
The blueberry took over completely.
Man, this game is addicting.
The lows really make the highs in this game.
Like so many other roguelites.
Right, man, it's addicting.
I'll see you guys in the next stream, soon.
Ciao.